<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2199" moduleid="11360" modulename="label" contextid="86610">
  <label id="2199">
    <name>It is important to think about what to measure bef...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span id="gmail-docs-internal-guid-a8b49071-7fff-be5d-7fe6-709333fe448a"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;It is important to think about what to measure before deciding to measure it - putting the time in before can save a lot of time after. This should be a conscious choice.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;An example that highlights the need for thoughtful consideration from the field concerns &lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-522af7e8-7fff-84bb-eb34-ce8ee3e3a06e"&gt;conducting a study to determine the variables that influence crop yield. To do this, they&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;measured the plant height as a measurement for the yield.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;We collected the height of five random plants and measured them as they grew, but no objective corresponded to this. Some of the breeds of crops are taller than other - but this is learnt in the breeding process, so what extra is learnt now?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;When we analysed the heights in a workshop, some varieties are taller than others. But, so what? Nothing new is learnt from measuring the plant heights.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Measuring plant height can be time-consuming, and it might not correspond to the objective of the study. In the beginning of the breeding programme, perhaps the plant height is important. But, at the end of the programme, how does this information contribute to the overall study objectives? We will see at the end that a short variety is relatively short, but “so what?”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Say that the study looks at different crop varieties, then it is important to ask at the start of the study: What is a suitable outcome variable here? Is the data we get relevant to our objectives?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Alternatively, it may be that measuring height of the yield is a valid measurement for the outcome variable, but this is time consuming. Is the data we get from this worth the work?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;In such cases, seeking input from domain experts can provide valuable insights into the relevance and significance of these variables in relation to the research focus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692884583</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>