<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2291" moduleid="11531" modulename="label" contextid="86817">
  <label id="2291">
    <name>Impactful reports tell a story. How you tell this ...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impactful reports tell a story. How you tell this story and share your findings publicly depends on the people who were involved in your research and the audience you are targeting for your report.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;When sharing your research findings, it helps to identify a central story or message that you want to convey. Think about:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the setting, in this case the background of your study;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the main character, that is the object of your study;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the plot, which is the problem or challenge your study is trying to solve;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the climax, that is your study findings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Sometimes you’ll want to tell the story of your whole study, sometimes you’ll want to focus on just one aspect of your study. The story you tell depends on your audience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;How you tell this story also depends on the audience. Firstly, consider how those involved in your study would like to be represented: do they want to be identifiable? Would they like to be named in photographs? Does it depend on how you are portraying them?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The richness and depth of qualitative research is in the data itself, and so to accurately convey the meanings, research reports should include some of this data. This most commonly takes the form of direct quotes or photographs, so questions of anonymity and representation are important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Secondly, who should you share your research findings with? The people involved in your research and who it depends on; other researchers; policymakers etc.? The format of your report will depend on your target audience: you may want to focus on making it accessible to farmers, so meetings, posters, videos, or even theatre can be options; or if your audience is academic then you will veer towards journal articles and conference presentations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;When writing academic articles, the question of audience comes up again as each journal has a different audience. It’s important to get to know what journals exist and what their focus is - whether it’s theoretical, geographical, topic based. Communicating with academics will include mention of your research methods, to demonstrate the validity of your data and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693225778</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>