<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2181" moduleid="11322" modulename="label" contextid="86331">
  <label id="2181">
    <name>Background to the Data

Schlet et al (2022) anal...</name>
    <intro>&lt;h2&gt;Background to the Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0276580"&gt;Schlet et al (2022)&lt;/a&gt; analysed the Omani data to investigate the effect of modernisation in the Jabal Al Akhdar region of northern Oman. The background information given in this section draws upon the research conducted by Schlet et al (2022).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For centuries, the Mountain Oases in Oman have served as crucial providers of ecosystem services to households, while also holding significant local economic and cultural importance. Following the opening of a highway 15 years ago, there has been a notable increase in the number of both regional and international tourists to the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the initial stages of transformative processes in 2007, an extensive survey was undertaken encompassing all households situated within three primary settlements: namely Sharayjah, Qasha, and Masyrat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This survey was subsequently replicated in 2018, again covering the households in these three settlements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey encompassed a range of aspects, split into separate sheets in the data:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
Household data: &lt;/strong&gt;Demographic and household inquiries such as gender distribution, household size, age demographics, marital statuses, school attendance, and expenses.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Farmland: &lt;/strong&gt;Farm land size in 2007, of the households surveyed in 2007.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crop cultivation:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Crops planted, along with challenges and opportunities in crop cultivation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Livestock keeping:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Livestock amounts, along with challenges and opportunities in crop cultivation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animal numbers by decade: &lt;/strong&gt;Number of different livestock amounts from 1988 to 2018&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perceptions of farm tasks: &lt;/strong&gt;The farmers perception on different tasks concerning the farm&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing farm products:&lt;/strong&gt; Products sold by the farm, alongside retailers and preferences.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Views about farming and tourism: &lt;/strong&gt;The farmers perceptions on the future of the farm and tourism.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The collected data aims to portray the responses provided by each household to the survey questions, offering insights into various aspects of life and livelihood within these settlements.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692654170</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>