<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2209" moduleid="11389" modulename="label" contextid="86640">
  <label id="2209">
    <name>The video here below gives a brief example when me...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;The video &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1NdwKii4TPQGJj5LkhZ5ZrnZS5JC1qQrI/view?usp=sharing"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; below gives a brief example when measuring or ignoring in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The script to the video is given here:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;One example where we choose between measuring and ignoring variables is with an experiment where the outcome is the yield of millet. In this experiment, we want&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;to know the weight of millet to know the yield.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;Basically the question was with millet should you be measuring the weight of the whole stem or just the grains?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;You're interested in the grains - that's what you eat, and what you actually want to know,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;but measuring the grains and just the grains, is difficult: W&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;hen in the field and harvesting, the grains are on the stems. It is&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;later outside of the field that it is processed, and the grains are taken off&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;So&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;how reliable is the weight of the stem with the grains on it to be able to estimate the weight of the grain? To answer this, we&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;used other research to establish the weight of the stems &lt;strong&gt;is &lt;/strong&gt;reliable for the weight of the grains to be able to use the weight of the stems to estimate the weight of the grains.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;We found it was really reliable,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;and not only that, but it avoided all these other problems, &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nd &lt;/strong&gt;it was cheaper. It&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;enabled people to scale out the whole process: measuring stems in the field is really easy and worked really well. On the back of that, chose in future years to only measure the stems. S&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;o we had multiple wins.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;At the heart of this, it&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;wouldn't have worked if not for the reliability between the stem weight and the grain weight.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;That relationship was checked, and it was found that that relationship is reliable enough to use the stem weight to estimate the grain weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;This "stem weight" is then considered a proxy variable, we use the stem weight to calculate the grain weight.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693237981</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>