<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2260" moduleid="11476" modulename="label" contextid="86732">
  <label id="2260">
    <name>In the PICSA case study, a survey was conducted to...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-48da457b-7fff-ce56-9523-3906c0c99b5b"&gt;In the &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=14" target="_blank"&gt;PICSA case study&lt;/a&gt;, a survey was conducted to assess the effectiveness of PICSA training, involving 416 households from 20 communities chosen at random.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-48da457b-7fff-ce56-9523-3906c0c99b5b"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;One principle central to the PICSA approach is 'options by context.' This principle recognises the individuality of farmers, considering their distinct resource access, social characteristics, risk attitudes, and goals. Farmers' suitable and intriguing options are likely to vary, highlighting the need for personalised approaches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;This foundational concept guides not only the training but also the survey's design. As exemplified in the paper, “PICSA is designed for use with farmers irrespective of their level of literacy and has been successfully used with farmer who are non-literate.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;In the survey's creation, this perspective remains integral. Both literate and illiterate farmers' viewpoints are equally valued, demonstrated by employing enumerators to verbally administer the survey. This inclusive design aspect represents just one instance of the considerations incorporated into the PICSA survey's structure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;It is important to acknowledge “Options by context” when analysing data as well. Rarely does a universally 'best' solution exist, emphasising the necessity of context-sensitive approaches. For example, differences in desired crop season lengths among farmers can mean different solutions are required for different farmers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reference:&amp;nbsp;Clarkson, G., Dorward, P., Osbahr, H., Torgbor, F. and Kankam-Boadu, I., 2019. An investigation of the effects of PICSA on smallholder farmers’ decision-making and livelihoods when implemented at large scale–The case of Northern Ghana.&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Climate Services&lt;/i&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;14&lt;/i&gt;, pp.1-14.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693237009</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>