<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2640">
  <number>37</number>
  <name>Introduction: data flows in PICSA's evaluation</name>
  <summary>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;We can think of the research process as a flow, cycle or loop of data. The loop starts with the identification of what data will answer the research question, which suggests the study type and methods needed to collect the data. The flow continues to consider how the data collected can be analysed, interpreted and shared with others, then the loop closes as the data is used to inform or improve the situation of the ‘data originators’. The results of the study highlight new or additional avenues for research; and the flow starts all over again!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;If we think of &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=14"&gt;the research process as a flow of data&lt;/a&gt;, we see that every key research decision has an impact on the data and as researchers we need to consider what are the implications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;In the paragraph from the Participatory Integrated Climate Services for Agriculture (PICSA) study below, we see that careful thought was given to this data flow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-8c1e9d5f-7fff-ae5b-b24e-8a730bd8da98"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The survey and case studies were conducted several months after the 2015 season so after crop, livestock and other livelihood enterprises had been operating for several months following the PICSA activities. The survey and case studies between them investigated what PICSA training farmers had taken part in, what if any changes farmers had made to their crop, livestock or other livelihoods as a result of the PICSA approach, and farmers’ perceptions of the effects of the changes on production and their households… The qualitative case studies, through in-depth discussion, interviewing and observation, also allowed for triangulation to ensure correct attribution of changes and reported effects due to the PICSA training. The research focused mainly on whether and how PICSA influenced farmers’ behaviours, and at farmers’ perceptions of the effects of their changed behaviours. It also explored farmers’ perceptions of their ability and confidence to make decisions, and deal with climate related challenges etc. The research did not seek to look for changes in outputs (e.g. yields) or resources available to households (e.g. assets) through comparison ‘before and after’ or ‘with and without’ being involved with the PICSA approach. Variation in rainfall between years (as well as in economic and social conditions) would have considerable influence on production and assets, and it would not be feasible to isolate the effects of farmers’ decisions from these...” Pages 5-6.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-8c1e9d5f-7fff-ae5b-b24e-8a730bd8da98"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Graham Clarkson, Peter Dorward, Henny Osbahr, Francis Torgbor, Isaac Kankam-Boadu, 2019.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;An investigation of the effects of PICSA on smallholder farmers’ decision-making and livelihoods when implemented at large scale – The case of Northern Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Climate Services&lt;/em&gt;, 14: 1-14.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The researchers considered what data could feasibly be collected, what data should be collected to answer their research questions, and how this data should be analysed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s interesting about this study from the methodology perspective is that the researchers highlight that they verified the quality of their data. How did they do this? They compared the results between their different research methods to ensure data was consistent and that their analysis was correct.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can also see how the research process can be thought of as a data loop in this case study; where the findings of the research support the people who created the data and generate new situations or research questions. PICSA are evaluating their method for supporting agricultural climatology knowledge amongst smallholder farmers, and so their long term aim is to better understand the benefits and challenges of the method to better support more farmers. We can however ask whether the survey and case studies were of any benefit to the farmers involved, or if it would only benefit the next participants in the PICSA approach? So for example, it would be interesting to know if the survey both served to collect data and to share knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>11294</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>{"op":"&amp;","c":[],"showc":[]}</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>1692563129</timemodified>
  <course_format_options id="967">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>collapsed</name>
    <value>0</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="965">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>parent</name>
    <value>36</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="966">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>visibleold</name>
    <value>1</value>
  </course_format_options>
</section>