<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2279" moduleid="11515" modulename="label" contextid="86799">
  <label id="2279">
    <name>Qualitative data takes many forms, from sketches, ...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Qualitative data takes many forms, from sketches, audio recordings to field notes and diaries. In the selected excerpts from the &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=14" target="_blank"&gt;Participatory Integrated Climate Services for Agriculture (PICSA) article&lt;/a&gt;, we see that the researchers collated data from their discussions, interviews and observations in written notes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The qualitative case studies, through in-depth discussion, interviewing and observation, also allowed for triangulation to ensure correct attribution of changes and reported effects due to the PICSA training…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The evidence in Table 3 again demonstrates the sheer variety of different changes that resulted from farmers engaging with the PICSA approach. Crops, livestock and other livelihood changes that include new crop varieties, changes in scale of planted crops and rate of input application, changes in planting date, weeding regimes, management of livestock (feeding, veterinary regimes inter alia) and beginning new and changing management of ‘other livelihood’ enterprises (food crop selling and firewood selling). Also striking is the range of impacts reported where common themes include improved food security, paying children’s school fees, re-investing profits in agriculture, livestock or in improving household structures…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;b id="docs-internal-guid-ba49ad5d-7fff-fffb-7dba-bf560b06f9e4"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/3MLhUtc6WU-AUpVzZMYZ9MpZGjTXRna5jz2gkd9hcoG12RnIVxxzLGNFEVL18uf4LEp96NQWZe9E_QXrWTHb6sEC14i0K6UkzSmK-a4rolTB1li6Mr4_HPa_58jZJ1XmDpudecLApG9FOaOGmLQtmt0" width="624" height="264"&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Farmer NGP198Q decided on the back of the training to diversify her livelihood and ensure she was not ‘only diverting her effort into one area’.” Pages 5-6.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Graham Clarkson, Peter Dorward, Henny Osbahr, Francis Torgbor, Isaac Kankam-Boadu, 2019. An investigation of the effects of PICSA on smallholder farmers’ decision-making and livelihoods when implemented at large scale – The case of Northern Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Climate Services&lt;/em&gt;, 14: 1-14.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;What form do you think this original data was collected in? Was it audio recordings, videos, or written notes? Does it matter what form the data took? It depends on the use of the data, what equipment or constraints the researchers were working within, and of course it depends on their expertise and not only their personal preferences, but the interviewees preferences too. Audio and video recordings provide rich data, but take a long time to transcribe. Written notes can be succinct and time effective, but accurate note-taking is a skill and the researcher runs the risk of missing something, or inaccurately recording what someone said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Like quantitative data, you start analysing qualitative data as soon as it comes in, and if you are collecting it yourself then the analysis starts during the collection process as you observe and engage in conversation. This helps you identify a suitable structure for your analyses. The PICSA study will have collected several types of data for each household they created a case study about, and so we can safely assume that they grouped - or coded - the different data types by household. In Table 3 of the excerpt, the researchers also differentiated the data, or coded it, according to what changes the farmer made following PICSA training, and what self-identified impact this had on their farm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Triangulation is used in data analysis and it requires structured data - so that you can compare like with like. The PICSA study will have triangulated individual farm-level data, but also compared these farm case studies with their quantitative survey data to ensure an accurate understanding of the individual farm practices. The use of mixed methods calls for an analysis which compares the data between these methods to ensure the validity of each data and their analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693379938</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>