<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2627">
  <number>25</number>
  <name>Illustrative example: reading about pearl millet biofortification</name>
  <summary>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There is so much literature available related to your study, how can you find your way and make the most of it? Let's consider a section from &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=12"&gt;the pearl millet crop selection case study&lt;/a&gt;, an&amp;nbsp;article by Pucher et al. (2014) entitled: Micronutrient Density and Stability in West African Pearl Millet - Potential for Biofortification.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-bcbf4595-7fff-eaaa-f406-8e0a3e15e9b7"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Biofortification is the process of increasing the nutrient densities by breeding or genetic engineering. Biofortification of staple crops can be a sustainable and cost-effective approach to combating malnutrition (Bouis, 1999; Meenakshi et al., 2010), especially of rural populations in remote, low-rain fall areas, with limited access to diverse diets, commercially fortified foods, or supplements (Saltzman et al., 2013). Pearl millet, the most heat-tolerant and one of the most drought- and salinity-tolerant cultivated cereals, is a major food crop for smallholder subsistence farmers living on marginal agricultural lands in the semiarid tropics of Africa and Asia (Haussmann et al., 2012). Pearl millet grain has a relatively well-balanced amino acid composition suitable for human nutrition and higher grain fat,&amp;nbsp; protein, and micronutrient densities than other major cereals like wheat (Triticum aestivum L.), maize, or polished rice (Oryza sativa L.) (Goswami et al., 1969; Sawaya et al.,&amp;nbsp; 1984; Khairwal et al., 1999; Dwivedi et al., 2012; Bashir&amp;nbsp; et al., 2013). However, diets predominated by pearl millet are often not high enough in mineral micronutrient density to meet daily minimum requirements. The development of pearl millet varieties with improved grain mineral nutrient densities can be one step to improve the nutrient intake of rural families, especially in the Sahel region of sub-Saharan Africa where pearl millet can contribute 80 to 85% of daily calorie intake.” Pp1709-1710.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-bcbf4595-7fff-eaaa-f406-8e0a3e15e9b7"&gt;Pucher, Anna, Henning Høgh-Jensen, Jadah Gondah, C. Tom Hash et Bettina IG Haussman. 2014. Micronutrient Density and Stability in West African Pearl Millet - Potential for Biofortification. &lt;em&gt;Crop Scienc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt;. 54:1709–1720.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-bcbf4595-7fff-eaaa-f406-8e0a3e15e9b7"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;How did you read this text? Did you read it all quickly? Did you read some bits more slowly? Why?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;How you read and what you get out of a text will depend on what your own research is about. There’s not just one way of reading texts: as so long as it’s good research, it’s not the text itself that determines how it’ll be read, but you and your research’s relationship to it. So what you focus on within a text depends on why you’re reading it and what your research question is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Are you doing research about pearl millet and malnutrition? Then this whole paragraph by Pucher et al. will be directly relevant to you and you should read it slowly to get the most out of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Most of us aren’t doing research on exactly that topic though. A researcher interested in sustainable and cost-effective approaches to combatting malnutrition may skim read the paragraph, but slow down at the mention of the two relevant texts: Bouis (1999) and Meenakshi et al. (2010). They would look at the reference section to identify these texts and decide whether they can inform their study. Similarly, a researcher in food supplements should consider what research Saltzman et al. (2013) have conducted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>11283</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>{"op":"&amp;","c":[],"showc":[]}</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>1692563459</timemodified>
  <course_format_options id="928">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>collapsed</name>
    <value>0</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="926">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>parent</name>
    <value>24</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="927">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>visibleold</name>
    <value>1</value>
  </course_format_options>
</section>