<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2248" moduleid="11464" modulename="label" contextid="86720">
  <label id="2248">
    <name>What does it mean to optimise bean production in E...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;What does it mean to optimise bean production in Ethiopia? Does this mean maximising the yield of dried beans for human consumption? What variety of bean are we interested in and why? Are there other uses of beans beyond human consumption that we should consider? What about the bean plant; what uses does it have?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Each crop has multiple uses and beans are an interesting example of this multidimensionality on a farm. This multidimensionality comes out in &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Abera2020_Article_DiversityUseAndProductionOfFar.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Abera et al.’s study&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;em&gt;Diversity, use and production of farmers’ varieties of common bean (Phaseolus vulgaris L., Fabaceae) in southwestern and northeastern Ethiopia&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use values of common bean&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Farmers identified six uses of common bean [in Ethiopia]; the diversity of uses was higher in the NE than in the SW. The vast majority of farmers in both production areas reported planting common bean as food for their household (Fig. 6). Key informants described how common bean is prepared as a stew, either SHIRO WOT (roasted ground seeds combined with spices including hot pepper) or KIK WOT (split grains simmered with spicy hot pepper). Common beans are also used to prepare NEFRO (dry or fresh common bean grains boiled with whole maize grains). Farmers in both production areas sell common bean in their local markets as a source of income. Farmers in the NE described several other uses, including as medicine for people and livestock. For example, eating boiled grains on an empty stomach is said to reduce gastric pain. According to key informants, common bean grains are soaked and boiled in salty water and fed to animals, particularly cows affected by drought. Farmers in the NE use common bean residues (stems, leaves, and pods) to feed livestock, whereas, in the SW, common bean residue is not an important source of livestock feed because the long growing period provides abundant alternative sources of fodder. In the NE, the importance of common bean as fodder is greater than grass pea (Lathyrus sativus), another important food and fodder crop. A small number of farmers in the NE mentioned that common bean flowers provide nectar for honeybees.” Page 7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;b id="docs-internal-guid-c90942ea-7fff-3cef-9df1-442ef0f2314a"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/7vR5GMDrmF9u0IEOWjNum5w2irmSW7wxMFzuZxwphhRG2oxV8uveP6v7HzdB8AsqtBpnKYFc1GPveIrgS4mPh9pyFg_NjVsXfg0ydRBv3IENIVni30XhHvdcvwLtyX_CzFvaNBisyldf1wDUvXUPWFs" width="624" height="305"&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span&gt;B. Abera, M. Berhane, A. Nebiyu, M. L. Ruelle, A. McAlvay, Z. Asfaw, A. Tesfaye and Z. Woldu. 2020. Diversity, use and production of farmers’ varieties of common bean (Phaseolus vulgaris L., Fabaceae) in southwestern and northeastern Ethiopia. &lt;em&gt;Genetic Resources and Crop Evolution&lt;/em&gt;. 67: 339–356.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;What does this diversity of uses of the bean tell us? It helps identify people’s interest and motivations for growing beans, which indicates to researchers what bean characteristics are wanted where. From this study, we see that plant breeders should research how to maximise bean production, and for farmers in the North East of the country, fodder production too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;We need to dig deeper into this idea of multidimensional maximisation. Let’s look at the idea of bean production. The beans are food human consumption so the bean varieties need to take into account the nutritional content. We are therefore not only interested the yield, but the nutritional value of this yield. We also need to consider the consumers’ preferences about varieties, whether that is due to taste, cost, or other factors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;An important use value of beans that is not mentioned in the article is the benefits they may provide to the soil health. Beans are a legume, and many legumes are known for their ability to fix nitrogen, an essential nutrient for all plants, in the soil. Alternatively, composting the residues can help improve soil fertility. Growing a diversity of crops through the seasons helps reduce pests and diseases on a farm and might be another interesting dimension to consider.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The FAO principle of diversity, is the reason we need multienvironment trials and multidimensional studies. The same test can produce different results in different environments, but it can also have an impact on other dimensions of a farm.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693172766</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>