<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2298" moduleid="11561" modulename="label" contextid="86856">
  <label id="2298">
    <name>Weeds are normally considered in a negative light,...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-03abcfaa-7fff-a987-973b-25b38b36fe53"&gt;Weeds are normally considered in a negative light, as a plant which competes with the crop for nutrients and minerals in the soil. If we take a multidimensional approach to weeds, however, we can see them in a different light, and even as a potential resource.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-03abcfaa-7fff-a987-973b-25b38b36fe53"&gt;This is exemplified in the article Biomass Production, and Feed and Economic Value of Fodder Weeds as By-products of Millet Cropping in a Sahelian Farming System. The introductory paragraph below explains the reasons behind the study:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-03abcfaa-7fff-a987-973b-25b38b36fe53"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Pearl millet (Pennisetum glaucum (L.) R. Br.) is normally planted in June, at the beginning of the wet season. Generally weeds are thought to compete with crops for the mineral nutrients, moisture and light which are vital for establishment and early growth. A loss of 10–30 kg ha in millet grain yields has been estimated for every day that weeding in western Niger villages is delayed between planting and first weeding, and 5-30 kg ha for every day between first and second weeding (McIntire et al., 1989). In contrast, the occurrence of weeds after the flowering of millet, usually in July or August in Niger, about 40-60 days after planting, causes relatively little yield loss (Rao et al., 1989). Even though weeds are considered to cause more harm than good if not controlled, farmers are aware of the positive value of various dicotyledonous plants and grasses (Baidu-Forson, 1994). Information on the role of such wild plants in African societies is usually restricted to their uses as spices, medicines, toys or construction material (McGlothlen et al., 1986; Sindiga, 1994). Information on the nutritional value of weeds for livestock production in the WAS is limited, but results from other regions confirm that fodder weeds may be an important feed for livestock production (Derrick et al., 1993; Marten and Andersen, 1975). This study was therefore conducted to determine the dry matter production and nutritional and economic value of fodder weeds growing on cultivated millet fields at the onset of the dry season in Niger.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-03abcfaa-7fff-a987-973b-25b38b36fe53"&gt;Lamers, J., Buerkert, A., Makkar, H., Von Oppen, M., &amp;amp; Becker, K. 1996. Biomass Production, and Feed and Economic Value of Fodder Weeds as By-products of Millet Cropping in a Sahelian Farming System. &lt;em&gt;Experimental Agriculture&lt;/em&gt;, 32(3), 317-326.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693245005</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>