<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2269" moduleid="11500" modulename="label" contextid="86773">
  <label id="2269">
    <name>Qualitative research methods have an openness to r...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qualitative research methods have an openness to recording what is unknown or unexpected. Methods mainly feature open-ended questions, where the response needs more than a one word answer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Qualitative research methods use the same design principles as other research. The language used can be different, in particular the idea of structure is central to how people discuss qualitative studies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;For example interviews, which are one-on-one, can be:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;structured, having a pre-determined list of questions like in a questionnaire;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;semi-structured, having questions but being flexible and responsive to the answers and issues raised;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;unstructured, like a free discussion.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Standardisation of the data through structured methods supports easier comparison, whereas unstructured methods are more open to unexpected findings. It’s often useful to find a balance between these two approaches and this is why semi-structured methods are so common.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;A really useful qualitative tool is focus groups, which bring together people to work together and explore perspectives on a topic. They can be based around a discussion, or more active reflections. For both interviews and focus groups, it's easy to recognise the importance of design principles in sampling to avoid biases and misrepresentations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;This contrasts with participant observation, which is primarily an opportunistic research method, that has its roots in anthropology. Participant observation, like the name suggests, means observing while also participating. Being present, and participating, allows insight into what people do which they might not even be aware of! Anthropologists can therefore spend months doing participant observation to develop an understanding through physical activity and observation. They might assist a shopkeeper/market stallholder, to understand how trading occurs; or become a farm labourer, to get an inside perspective into the workings of a farm. Participant observation is primarily unstructured, but participation and/or observation can be given structure to ensure the collection of ethical data that will respond to your research questions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693215856</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>