<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="1587" moduleid="9179" modulename="label" contextid="82058">
  <label id="1587">
    <name>The Pearl Millet Growth case study aimed to unders...</name>
    <intro>&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-100622f5-7fff-35e6-c4e2-0e8f2836930a"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;The &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=12#section-12" target="_blank"&gt;Pearl Millet Growth case study&lt;/a&gt; aimed to understand what factors affected how pearl millet grew in different places. This was a 3-year experiment with millet and compared four specific data types to assess their effectiveness in reducing variation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;The physical layout of the treatments affects the comparison of treatments. Before performing the experiment, they checked the field to ensure that one area&amp;nbsp; of the field will not impact one treatment more than another area. They found that the field was mostly even, without any noticeable slopes, except for a few small spots that looked different. The cause of these spots were not identified initially, and hence they found that treatments could be completely randomised to the field.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;A farmer who used the site before it was fallowed in 1983 helped to identify the previous position of&amp;nbsp; trees, bushes, termite mounds, hard soil, and fertile areas. They categorised the plots into five categories based on this information. These five categories subsequently defined five blocks:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;(i) plots that formerly had hard pans, which are associated with bad millet growth;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;(ii) plots with former bushes and trees;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;(iii) plots with termite mounds;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;(iv) areas of former trash disposal that were associated with good millet growth; and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;(v) all other plots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;The blocks reduced variation on low- but not high-productive plots for the first year. However, in subsequent years, the blocks did not account for the variation in the yield. However, that does not mean that the efforts were in vain - it is important to think about these things, account for them, and use blocking.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/9Oc0Jo0P5UMuwnul5d7Ggym1u6M9UgNDWXzy7xgmqUDSft5Shne239iBf9WjcdAV9tNhibngq05INYcwNtC4Zvz8ZQlrA7GnK7BE3kngch458B3u-MC3pmyGF8hDXk6Z1P1jHo84bc8Gvmfc-i7KFEk" width="624" height="487"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;In the analysis, the researchers found from the distribution of residuals an indication of a gradient from west to east (Figure 1, note that West is placed towards the bottom row of the plot). They hypothesise this is due to a major pest, the cotton stainer, in the west of the field.&amp;nbsp; So, they included the distance from the west as a factor in their analysis. This split the field into eight sections, each with 12 plots. The pattern from west to east was most obvious for grain yield than other yields:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;“The post stratification of the experiment in the west— east direction contributed significantly to the explanation of total variation. This was indicated by [...] the decrease of residual mean squares for grain yield by 23%”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/Kmj2hl8iT4ka1Jj1UN_f02OD5Cn3_TQSirlsHUvcXX9ESF_QXSXINvg3LKB0OQ_N8vsYcT5w5TLX_YenUnoUq-OtxCXy6RV_blK1WMSc3gjwY1DdrgsVJfvxEoap9r9dzN5AprAGTxOGgdEq6X8VyLI" width="522" height="769"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693238290</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>