<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2275" moduleid="11510" modulename="label" contextid="86794">
  <label id="2275">
    <name>As researchers we want to create positive change, ...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;As researchers we want to create positive change, but our good intentions alone aren’t enough to prevent us from causing harm. That’s why research has to include proper consideration of potential ethical issues, risks and unintended consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The excerpt from &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=16" target="_blank"&gt;Schlecht et al.’s study&lt;/a&gt; highlights some of the broad ethical considerations involved in their research. Can you identify which potential issues the research team thought about? Why are they potential ethical issues and what impact could they have - and on whom or what?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In spring 2007 and in spring 2018, a participatory survey was conducted at the three locations. It addressed HH [head of the household] characteristics (demography, education, income sources, physical assets), cropping system (area managed, crops cultivated, inputs used), livestock keeping (species and numbers, feeding practices), use of agricultural labour, crop and livestock sales (including product processing and marketing), and major problems as well as opportunities of crop and livestock farming. Prior to conducting the survey, the underlying questionnaire was discussed with senior colleagues at Sultan Qaboos University, who alleged that it met the ethical and cultural requirements for interviews in Oman. Questions were fully compliant with national and local norms, values and traditions and did not allow identifying human subjects or disclosing private information. After its general approval, the survey’s purpose was explained to all interviewees; they were assured that participation in the survey was voluntary, anonymous, not related to any government activities, and that participation or avoidance would not reap any benefit or disadvantage. An interview lasted on average 40 minutes; it only started if oral consent was given by the HH head who was male in all but one case in 2007 and 2018. Only thereafter, the individual interview was conducted with the HH head in Arabic language; the entire conversation took place in privacy within the family home or courtyard, to avoid any real or perceived pressure of third parties.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Schlecht E, Dickhoefer U, Aloufi S, Alqaisi O, Buerkert A. 2022. Showcasing the multifaceted aspects of agricultural transformation: The example of mountain oases in Oman. &lt;em&gt;PLoS ONE&lt;/em&gt; 17(11): e0276580.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Let’s look at this in order. Firstly, you often need permission to conduct research from relevant local, regional, or national institutions or parties. Schlecht et al. highlight the essential preparatory steps of obtaining research approval for the location of their study: in the first instance they ensure that their research would meet the national ethical guidelines - in this case those of Oman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Secondly, ethical research not only obtains relevant permissions but ensures that it is locally acceptable and relevant. Notice that Schlecht et al. consider the appropriateness of their research methods to the local culture. The local culture was for example taken into consideration here in deciding the language of the interview, and the relatively private location of the interviews. Other aspects could have been considered such as the interviewee’s position within the household or implications of the time and timings of the interviews. Most importantly, local knowledge is essential to know what cultural considerations might be important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Schlecht et al. also highlight how they tried to ensure their research participants were actively engaged in the survey. There is a difference between being a research participant, who has no control of the study and is merely a source of data and participatory research. Participatory research can be one way of ensuring that research is locally acceptable and relevant and involves participants in anything from the analysis of the data, to several or all, aspects of the data flow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Thirdly, when collecting data the concept of informed consent becomes important. The meaning of informed consent depends on the context, and you need to consider who can give consent, how and what it means to be informed. The researchers in this study state that they ensured that their participants were told of the purpose of the study and what impact it might - and in this case might not - have on them. This, for Schlecht et al., allowed the participants to give their informed consent about whether they wanted to take part in the research. Do you agree? Note that the consent was given orally. Why do you think this might be? Oral consent might not be appropriate in all studies, can you conceive of a scenario where this might not be sufficient?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;There are a lot more ethical considerations in this study then what is mentioned in this section of their article and before fieldwork, the researchers will have conducted a much more in depth exploration of the potential ethical risks involved. These might have included potential risks to the researchers, but also considerations of the use of the data after collection, or the sharing of results after the study.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693217411</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>