<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2623">
  <number>21</number>
  <name>Illustrative example: the role of literature in the Pearl Millet growth article</name>
  <summary>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-5dfe5e94-7fff-8dc1-1aa5-cf25b388283b"&gt;A literature review is important both when you’re planning and writing up your research. This is highlighted using the &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=13" target="_blank" title="case study on Soil Variability and Pearl Millet Growth in the Sahel"&gt; case study on Soil Variability and Pearl Millet Growth in the Sahel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-5dfe5e94-7fff-8dc1-1aa5-cf25b388283b"&gt;At the planning phases, it’s an opportunity for you to ensure that your work is relevant - theoretically and contextually - and to find out what is already known about a subject.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-5dfe5e94-7fff-8dc1-1aa5-cf25b388283b"&gt;At the writing up stage, a literature review introduces others to your study and highlights it’s connections with other research.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-5dfe5e94-7fff-8dc1-1aa5-cf25b388283b"&gt;Consider this paragraph from an article by &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/14Ck-KrFiyJcDUOcF0LwIPTJHYk_qr423/view?usp=drive_link" target="_blank" title="Buerkert et al. 1995"&gt;Buerkert et al. 1995&lt;/a&gt; on the effect of treatments on the growth of Pearl Millet in the Sahel.&amp;nbsp;What role do the references play in the paragraph?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-5dfe5e94-7fff-8dc1-1aa5-cf25b388283b"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“SPATIAL VARIABILITY OF THE SOIL, reflected in poorly understood differences in plant growth over short distances, may hinder the analysis of data from field experiments and the detection of treatment effects (Moormann and Kang, 1978; Wendt et a1., 1993; Wilding and Hossner, 1989). The problem is particularly severe when research is conducted with millet on recently cleared acid sandy soils of the Sahel with an unknown history of land use by local farmers. In sub-Saharan Africa, therefore, field experiments (especially experiments of plant physiologists, nutritionists, and breeders that go beyond basic agronomy) are frequently conducted at sites of high uniformity that are not typical for the region. On-station research has shown that one way to increase uniformity of plant growth in the Sahel is ridging, which improves plant stands and total biomass (Klaij and Hoogmoed, 1993). However, the search for spatial uniformity by researchers misses the opportunity to test interactions between treatment effects and inherent soil productivity.” p1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-5dfe5e94-7fff-8dc1-1aa5-cf25b388283b"&gt;Buerkert, Andreas, Roger D. Stern, and Horst Marschner. 1995. Post Stratification Clarifies Treatment Effects on Pearl Millet Growth in the Sahel. Agronomy Journal 87(4): 752-761.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-5dfe5e94-7fff-8dc1-1aa5-cf25b388283b"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Let’s start with the first sentence: the first three references all go together and credit the other researchers who have identified the theoretical issue of how to understand soil variability over small areas. The sentence underpins the whole research and forms the basis for their research question. Having three references shows that the problem has been observed by several other researchers and yet no solution has yet been found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;At the end of the paragraph there’s a reference to research by Klaij and Hoogmoed. This reference credits Klaij and Hoogmoed for their on-station research that demonstrated that plant stands and biomass are uniformly improved by ridging, but it also has the added benefit of passing on responsibility if ever there were issues with this solution. Buerkert, Stern, and Marschner are actually protecting themselves by crediting other researchers for their findings! If Buerkert, Stern, and Marschner had not provided a reference for this finding, readers would assume that it was them who had discovered the effects of ridging. That probably sounds fine so far, but as a researcher, how would you defend yourself if, for example, in years to come other researchers discovered some harmful side-effects of ridging and blame you rather than the actual researchers, for having explored this as a solution? (Please note that we’re not suggesting that there are actually issues with Klaij and Hoogmoed’s work!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;It’s better for everyone if you reference where you got the ideas and research findings that you are mentioning - both in presentations and in your written work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>9182,11280</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>{"op":"&amp;","c":[],"showc":[]}</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>1692608255</timemodified>
  <course_format_options id="916">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>collapsed</name>
    <value>0</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="914">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>parent</name>
    <value>20</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="915">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>visibleold</name>
    <value>1</value>
  </course_format_options>
</section>