<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2224" moduleid="11421" modulename="label" contextid="86672">
  <label id="2224">
    <name>The researchers investigated factors that increase...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-1678da77-7fff-205a-3ded-fbe7c8a39ebd"&gt;The researchers investigated factors that increased millet straw yield in the &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=13#section-13" target="_blank"&gt;Case Study on&amp;nbsp;Pearl Millet Growth in the Sahel&lt;/a&gt;. In this experiment, there were 48 combinations of treatments to investigate. While still a relatively large experiment, resources are scarce and hence data was limited. As a result, careful design was important, and hypothesis testing was used to validate that the differences found are not random.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-1678da77-7fff-205a-3ded-fbe7c8a39ebd"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;They found several treatments and interactions of treatments affected the outcome variable. This was found with the help of hypothesis testing. An extract from the paper, alongside Table 1 that is referred to is given here:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;em&gt;The repeated measures analyses showed that productivity strata defined with the help of the score residuals, genotype, crop residues (CR), and broadcast P application explained a significant proportion of total variation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;em&gt;There were significant interactions of genotype x year (which may also reflect the change in genotypes) and of genotype x CR for both straw and grain yield. Whereas average straw yields remained similar over years, average grain yields, the effects of stratum on grain yields, and of both CR and P on straw and grain yields, changed over time (Table 1).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/Hg8N5rSkfkpXubMuz0P9LqDrjIEv7UMDZH6KNtL0SkT1xbqgV8pr7yKtWX4QTteQSeuoCqx42xUuPqSzk2lj_-eoaqyNWt0VJCZe5ZS1abvfynG_jC13tvY9-kFO-3nXY85jM1-fBWLz35zsgaw5mlU" width="533" height="600"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;The significant p-values indicate that there is enough data to draw reliably that the observed differences in the score residuals, genotype, crop residues, and broadcast application&amp;nbsp; are not merely due to chance, and instead these variables account for a significant proportion of total variation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693238707</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>