<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2201" moduleid="11364" modulename="label" contextid="86614">
  <label id="2201">
    <name>The concept of variability is important: The objec...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-7a512d07-7fff-9c52-5a4b-37bf4acc68b9"&gt;The concept of variability is important: The objective of a statistician is to identify variables that contribute to the variability in the outcome variable. &lt;strong&gt;In essence, statisticians seek to uncover what influences the outcome variable - what variables account for the variability, or "fluctuations", in the outcome?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-7a512d07-7fff-9c52-5a4b-37bf4acc68b9"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Within the dataset, there exists a total level of variability in the outcome variable. To gain a clearer understanding, we can attribute a portion of this variability to different variables and examine how each of these variables impacts the outcome. Is there a relationship between the outcome and the variable? Does the explanatory variable account for variability observed in the outcome?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;This process naturally leads us to the question of unaccounted-for variability. How much of the initial total variability is still not accounted for? This is just the difference between the total variability and the portion that is accounted for by specific variables.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;In other words, the types of variability are:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;1. Accounted for Variability: This accounts for the variance in the outcome variable that can be accounted-for using the variables present in the dataset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;2. Unaccounted-for Variability: This is the variability in the outcome variable that has not been attributed. This may be due to random natural fluctuations, or potential explanatory variables that are absent from the data, or have been excluded when so far in the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Consequently, the total variability comprises both the accounted-for and unaccounted-for forms of variability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692903291</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>