<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2198" moduleid="11359" modulename="label" contextid="86609">
  <label id="2198">
    <name>The Pearl Millet Growth case study aimed to examin...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-be554301-7fff-d089-837a-01cf088d172e"&gt;The &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=13#section-13" target="_blank"&gt;Pearl Millet Growth case study&lt;/a&gt; aimed to examine the factors influencing spatial variation in pearl millet growth. The study utilised a 3-year experiment with millet and compared four specific data types to assess their effectiveness in reducing variation unrelated to treatment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-be554301-7fff-d089-837a-01cf088d172e"&gt;These four data types to account for any variation in the growth of pearl millet are:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-be554301-7fff-d089-837a-01cf088d172e"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" role="presentation"&gt;Soil Chemical Data: This involves analysing the chemical composition of the topsoil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" role="presentation"&gt;Residuals of the first year’s yield data: This involves assessing the discrepancies between the expected and actual yields from the initial year&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" role="presentation"&gt;Traditional fertility classification system: This assesses soil fertility and its potential impact on growth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li dir="ltr" aria-level="1"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" role="presentation"&gt;Plant vigor scores: These measure the overall health and vitality of the plants.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The experiment found that soil chemical data did not significantly account for the overall variation observed in the data, but the other three data types did.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;These four data types were selected deliberately to account for variation in the outcome variable. Any data types not included were actively excluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;A lot of thought is required to determine variables to measure for the outcome in this study. All variables chosen are chosen to measure the outcome in order to answer their initial research question, while simultaneously suitable from a practical aspect. The researchers would have ensured that the measured variables work on a practical level: are they cost-effective? Time-effective? Can they be ethically sourced? Are these measurements expected to be correlated with pearl millet growth? Some compromises may need to be made, but those decisions are best made at the start of the study to maximise the usefulness of the study results.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Similarly, the experiment focused on specific variables and treatments, and any variables or treatments not included are also intentionally excluded. Any variables not included are variables that are actively excluded. If asked about the exclusion of certain variables, the researchers would need to justify their choices based on the study's objectives and design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693237959</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>