<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2636">
  <number>33</number>
  <name>Illustrative example: study types in the evaluation of the PICSA method</name>
  <summary>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-a4b30dc6-7fff-43ce-00af-44123c809146"&gt;Do you think some study types are better than others, or that some methods are better than others? Is quantitative data better than qualitative data? These are trick questions, but they’re not tricky questions. The type of study, the methods needed for the study, and the type of data needed all depend on your research question.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-a4b30dc6-7fff-43ce-00af-44123c809146"&gt;The &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=14" target="_blank" title="Participatory Integrated Climate Services for Agriculture (PICSA) study"&gt;Participatory Integrated Climate Services for Agriculture (PICSA) study &lt;/a&gt; for example explores the effects of PICSA on smallholder farmers’ decision-making and livelihoods in a particular instance involving hundreds of farmers. This is an open-ended research question, so we can suppose that they will include qualitative methods to understand the range of potential effects of the PICSA method. The scale of the study is also important to note, and it suggests quantitative survey type methods which have a broader reach. The paragraph below gives us more detail about the methods used, the data types they collected and the type of study it was.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-a4b30dc6-7fff-43ce-00af-44123c809146"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Ahead of any PICSA implementation in a new country or region of a country, a scoping visit is undertaken to introduce PICSA to potential partners, gather information on the agricultural systems and where necessary adapt specific parts of the approach to the local conditions, and to assess the availability and quality of historical meteorological data from rainfall stations…&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-a4b30dc6-7fff-43ce-00af-44123c809146"&gt;&lt;em&gt;As part of PICSA implementation there are monitoring sheets for agricultural field officers to fill out after every one of their meetings with groups of farmers. Farmers were interviewed for short surveys after steps G (when farmers make decisions about the coming season) and L (after the season). In addition to these short surveys, monitoring is conducted during the season through field visits by trained PICSA experts (those who help to train intermediaries). In the north of Ghana implementation in 2015 there were two separate visits by a research assistant who used observation, focus group discussions and in-depth individual interviews with farmers to investigate the impact that PICSA was having on households’ decision making. After the season a review meeting was held with all intermediaries that had been involved in the initial training and roll-out of the PICSA approach to be able to hear their thoughts and experiences and to provide support for their interactions with farmers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-a4b30dc6-7fff-43ce-00af-44123c809146"&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the north of Ghana, initial findings from these elements of PICSA monitoring helped to design a mixed methods approach that combined a quantitative survey of 416 randomly selected households that had received PICSA training and in depth qualitative case studies with 18 PICSA trained farmers. ” Page 5.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-a4b30dc6-7fff-43ce-00af-44123c809146"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Graham Clarkson, Peter Dorward, Henny Osbahr, Francis Torgbor, Isaac Kankam-Boadu, 2019&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;An investigation of the effects of PICSA on smallholder farmers’ decision-making and livelihoods when implemented at large scale – The case of Northern Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Climate Services&lt;/em&gt;, 14: 1-14.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-a4b30dc6-7fff-43ce-00af-44123c809146"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;It’s useful to differentiate between research methods and study types to better understand what the research is trying to achieve and what methods and data is needed to reach that goal. The three types of study - opportunistic, survey, experimental - are the difference between whether the study is designed, and whether it is testing causality. Research methods however determine what sorts of data is collected and how.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Let's look at what types of study are mentioned in this paragraph from the PICSA case study. Firstly, there’s an initial scoping visit which 1) surveys the general situation of local agricultural systems and 2) identifies what existing meteorological data exists in the region. This initial scoping visit brings together the opportunistic study type, which makes the most existing data, and the survey study type, which seeks a broad understanding of the current situation. Secondly, the PICSA case study is actually testing to see what impact their approach had with communities: this is testing causality, which is an experimental type of study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;It’s important to know the type of study your research uses, as this suggests what sort of data is needed. Indeed a research question, study type, and the data required are all connected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The PICSA study opportunistically uses existing quantitative meteorological data, where it exists, but we see that there are often access and quality issues with this second hand data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The PICSA study surveys the current state of agricultural systems, to have a baseline from which to design their interventions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The experimental aspect of the PICSA study uses a wider range of research methods to explore the impact of their approach and test its relevance and wider implications for the community. These methods include participant observation and focus groups, both of which are key qualitative methods, and the data collected can be anything from farm photos and handwritten notes to more structured transcriptions of interviews and related audio recordings. The PICSA study also uses a survey, which they state was quantitative. While surveys can create both qualitative and quantitative data, PICSA wanted to efficiently analyse a large quantity of data so they created a quantitative survey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;You do need to be pragmatic in choosing research methods and data types, as you have to consider how much time you have, what resources are available, and what skills or expertise you have available to you. For PICSA, they knew they could achieve breadth and depth through their mixed methods approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>11286</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>{"op":"&amp;","c":[],"showc":[]}</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>1692556237</timemodified>
  <course_format_options id="955">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>collapsed</name>
    <value>0</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="953">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>parent</name>
    <value>32</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="954">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>visibleold</name>
    <value>1</value>
  </course_format_options>
</section>