<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="1586" moduleid="9178" modulename="label" contextid="82057">
  <label id="1586">
    <name>If a Treatment is Present, it is an Experiment:Con...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-363dea04-7fff-df1a-9994-52f08642e3f3"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If a Treatment is Present, it is an Experiment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;Consider an experiment that aims to assess the effect of a fertiliser on crop yield. Here we may have two levels to examine for this treatment: the control, which may be the current standard fertiliser, and the experimental treatment, which may be the new fertiliser being tested.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;The field can be divided into two groups, with one group receiving the control treatment and the other receiving the experimental treatment. We can compare the performance of the experimental fertiliser to the standard one by analysing the impact of the two fertilisers on yield.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Here, we have a treatment, so this is an experiment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If a Treatment is Present, it is an Experiment, even if it "looks like" a survey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;You might have an experiment that “looks like” a traditional survey, or a survey that “looks like” a traditional experiment. For example, say you take soil samples from a field and analyse them in a lab - if there is no treatment, then this is just a survey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If a Treatment is not Present, it is not an Experiment, even if it doesn't "look like" it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;We might do a randomised controlled trial (RCT) in different farms with different interventions. The data collection might be using questionnaires, but because we have different interventions for the different farms, then we have a treatment effect. Hence, this is just an experiment. The differentiation between survey and experiment is not the presence of a questionnaire, it is simply just a treatment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693037597</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>