<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="1784" moduleid="10049" modulename="label" contextid="84110">
  <label id="1784">
    <name>We designed an experiment&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;analysed t...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href="$@QUIZVIEWBYID*9030@$" target="_blank" title="$@QUIZVIEWBYID*9030@$"&gt;designed an experiment&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=135" target="_blank" title="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=135"&gt;analysed the data&lt;/a&gt; to look at the effect of the treatments on the yield of tomatoes/millet. Following this, we &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=140" target="_blank" title="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=140"&gt;interpreted the results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to write a report of this trial from design to analysis to interpretation. It should be written as a short article, with the standard sections that such a report requires. The sections would normally be a brief summary, followed by the introduction, materials and methods, results and conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should assume that some readers are interested in the actual results, e.g. what is the effect of each factor.  Others are more interested in the design you used and your method of analysis, because they wish to adapt it to their own research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your answer refers to the two objectives in this report:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Our first objective is to recommend the strategy of growing tomatoes that maximises the yield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. The second objective is for the researchers to recommend the strategy of growing tomatoes/millet taking some account of cost of the different treatments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the Results:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We want a very brief overview of the results of the two experiments, together with your decisions on the importance of the 3 factors and which were the better treatments.&amp;nbsp; (You may not need to do much, if any, formal statistics. Your conclusions are likely to come from sensible comparisons of pairs, or small sets of yields).&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here you could mention the
economic aspects briefly. You should
also comment on the design. Did you need
both experiments? In hindsight could you
have designed the experiments better, etc?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693036253</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>