<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2659">
  <number>260</number>
  <name>Abstract Concept</name>
  <summary>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qualitative data comes in all shapes and sizes: to analyse it, it needs structure. &lt;/strong&gt;This includes open text, audio, photos, videos, drawings or fieldnotes made by those involved in the research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The same research design principles apply to qualitative research as to quantitative research; design helps you define the focus, plan how to treat variables, how to manage bias, and how to make comparisons. If data was collected through structured methods, this structure will provide you with a starting point for how to analyse the data. Like can be compared with like, and you might be able to quantify some results. Rich data will come from unexpected answers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;If data was collected through unstructured methods, however, you will have to identify a structure to begin the analysis. This can mean grouping the different themes raised to organise them along their similarities. For example, your research data might include photos of different crops. Depending on your research question, you might want to code crop photos together, according to the crop, the field, the season, or some combination of these. There is no one way to structure qualitative data, it just needs to reflect and help you answer your research question.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span&gt;There’s a chance that your data doesn’t however answer your research question, or you can’t get data which does answer your research question. Perhaps nobody bought the particular chemical fertiliser you were studying that year. In which case, you need to review your research question. This can be possible even after having collected data.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>11615</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>{"op":"&amp;","c":[],"showc":[]}</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>1693217868</timemodified>
  <course_format_options id="1024">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>collapsed</name>
    <value>0</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="1022">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>parent</name>
    <value>258</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="1023">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>visibleold</name>
    <value>1</value>
  </course_format_options>
</section>