<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2206" moduleid="11371" modulename="label" contextid="86621">
  <label id="2206">
    <name>Here we use an example with simulated data to see ...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here we use an example with simulated data to see about accounting for variability in our data. In this example, we have the outcome as Yield. We have three treatments: Fertiliser, Soil, and Variety.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e90a28bf-7fff-e8b5-f55e-5232a5cf3b0b"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We first add just Fertiliser to our data.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" aria-label="Console Output" role="document" id="rstudio_console_output"&gt;&lt;span tabindex="-1" role="document"&gt;           Df Sum Sq Mean Sq F value
Fertiliser  1   1.60   1.604  0.0783
Residuals  48 983.03  20.480      
&lt;/span&gt;Total      49 984.63         &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/span&gt;So what do we see? Our Fertiliser variable accounts for a very small amount of variability in the yield. This is evident by that the Fertiliser Mean Squares is very small compared to the Residuals Mean Squares. As a result, the F-value is very small at 0.0783.&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;The variability in the residuals should be just the variability that you get "by chance". We want the variability in the residuals to be just &lt;em&gt;random, natural &lt;/em&gt;variability, and to be about to account for all other variability through our variables.&lt;br&gt;By having a small F-value, this is suggesting that the variability in the factors is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;less than&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;the variability you get by chance. This is very unlikely, and so while this may be by chance, it is probably not by chance.&lt;br&gt;Instead, this implies that the residual variability contains within it stuff that is not random, but systematic. That is, there is still some variability in the model that is unaccounted for. This variability could be accounted for if you had the information.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fortunately, we have more information! &lt;strong&gt;We can add Soil to our model&lt;/strong&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" aria-label="Console Output" role="document" id="rstudio_console_output" style=""&gt;&lt;span tabindex="-1" role="document"&gt;           Df Sum Sq Mean Sq F value  
Fertiliser  1   1.60   1.604  0.0922 
&lt;/span&gt;Soil        1 165.19 165.186  9.4929 
Residuals  47 817.85  17.401         
Total      49 984.63           &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;Ok, so what do we see now? The variability accounted for by Fertiliser is very low still, but for Soil is now much higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;An&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;F value much greater than one implies that the variability in the Soil variable is much greater than the variability in the residuals. This suggests that the Soil variable accounts for a good amount of variability in the model. However, there's still a lot of unaccounted for variability.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, we add Variety:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" aria-label="Console Output" role="document" id="rstudio_console_output" style=""&gt;&lt;span tabindex="-1" role="document" style=""&gt;           Df Sum Sq Mean Sq  F value
Fertiliser  1   1.60    1.60   1.5241 
Soil        1 165.19  165.19 156.9571
Variety     1 769.43  769.43 731.1052
Residuals  46  48.41    1.05                    
Total      49 984.63&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;There's quite a bit to unpack here! Firstly, our Variety accounts for a very large amount of variability - the F value is very large, and the percentage of variability Variety accounts for is 769.43/984.63 * 100 = 78.1%! This implies that a large portion of the fluctuations in the yield comes down to the variety used itself. This is useful information when determining which variables impact the yield, and a good next step is to look at the data (such as means) to see how the two varieties impact the yield.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We can see from the plot that Variety 3 produces a higher yield than 1 or 2&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/image.png" alt="" role="presentation" class="img-fluid"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Secondly, our Fertiliser accounts for more variability now that additional variables are included. An F score roughly equivalent to 1 implies that the variability in the factor accounts for as much variability as if it were happening by chance. Fertiliser may account for variability in the yield.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Between all our variables, only 5% of variability is now unaccounted for in the data!&lt;br&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is simulated data, and we have exhausted all of our variables. This 48.41 residual variability is our variability that is left over. This residual variability has some natural variability in it, but it may also have some variability that could be accounted for by unmeasured variables.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692903306</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>