<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2126" moduleid="11207" modulename="label" contextid="86128">
  <label id="2126">
    <name>Articulate the information you want and how this w...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Articulate the information you want and how this will be obtained through a questionnaire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-ea94784d-7fff-31d3-a732-e1552d20797f"&gt;What data do you want to obtain and which questions can get you that data? For example, what statistical packages do people know how to use? Should this be asked as an open question, or will you limit the options to common statistical packages? Can people select multiple answers? What does it mean to know how to use a statistical package? What if people have experience with multiple packages but are more familiar with just one? What information are you wanting to capture, why will it be useful, and how will you do it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-ea94784d-7fff-31d3-a732-e1552d20797f"&gt;Other important information you may want to explore could be how much experience do they have with data sets, and what kind of data sets have they worked with etc. This sort of question could be very interesting and provide lots of detail, but how would you analyse it? If you’re not analysing it, why are you collecting it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-ea94784d-7fff-31d3-a732-e1552d20797f"&gt;What ethical considerations are there for this study? Are there any ways in which the survey can negatively affect people?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-ea94784d-7fff-31d3-a732-e1552d20797f"&gt;What biases might come out of your questionnaire? Might some questions be answered in a way which doesn’t reflect reality, and if so, how can you manage this? Think about how you should word the questions so that you are not implicitly suggesting answers? How do you want people to answer the questions so that people feel comfortable answering honestly?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-ea94784d-7fff-31d3-a732-e1552d20797f"&gt;As the results of this survey can also support a qualitative course evaluation, consider what information might be useful to understand learnings from the course. This might for example take the form of self-reported skill, confidence, importance, or enjoyment levels of research methods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692580905</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>