<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2134" moduleid="11215" modulename="label" contextid="86136">
  <label id="2134">
    <name>Create a short presentation (maximum 2 mins, 1 sli...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a short presentation (maximum 2 mins, 1 slide) to highlight a key learning from the study.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e09db341-7fff-1ceb-e85a-d40d9c861623"&gt;Communicating effectively is vital if you want your research findings to have impact. This means identifying the most important messages and learnings that your study identified and finding a way to communicate them in a clear and simple way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e09db341-7fff-1ceb-e85a-d40d9c861623"&gt;In a survey, you will have collected more data and information than you need to communicate. A short presentation cuts through all this ‘noise’ and can interest others in your study. Careful not to fall into the trap of confusing ‘noise’ with detail of data. Detail, like a quote, or a statistic, is vital evidence to include in study reports and should clearly support your interpretation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e09db341-7fff-1ceb-e85a-d40d9c861623"&gt;While the key outcomes should directly answer the research questions, there may be additional learnings that you choose to highlight. For example, were there challenges that you came up against and how did you solve them?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e09db341-7fff-1ceb-e85a-d40d9c861623"&gt;To best communicate your point, it can be helpful to think of the presentation as a story and to ask yourself: what is the story you want to tell?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692887640</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>