<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="1776" moduleid="10041" modulename="label" contextid="84091">
  <label id="1776">
    <name>In the context of agriculture, a second phase of t...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;In the context of agriculture, a second phase of the experiment can serve as a replication of the experiment,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;introducing more variability within the agricultural framework.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alternatively, the results obtained in the first phase &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;be used to inform the design of a subsequent phase.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;The purpose of the refinements in the design is to dig deeper to better understand the causal relationship between the treatments and the outcome variable.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;These refinements may come from aspects that have been found to be overlooked in the first phase, or may be prompted from the analysis of the first phase. For instance, the analysis from the data from the first phase design might prompt some conditions to be altered in the second phase. This can help identify any contextual factors that might influence the results to refine initial findings from the first phase and uncover new perspectives.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;In this sense, the first-phase of the experiment is like a "pilot study"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;. But then to get the replicated data, you might want a third-phase! We might not have the resources to spend on multiple years of an experiment. There&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;are good reasons to reflect after the first phase of an experiment, and the two phases may not achieve your objectives. So therefore you might not do a full scale experiment in the first year, but a smaller scale study, or a little pilot study if it is possible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;To avoid an experiment running over too many phases, it is important to design the first phase well to avoid multiple changes in future phases. The second phase of an experiment presents a valuable opportunity to either refine the experiment given the results in the first phase in the experiment, or to get more data as a "replication".&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692954102</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>