<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2633">
  <number>30</number>
  <name>Abstract Concept</name>
  <summary>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-dd6ac84f-7fff-9e5b-6725-a479a2ffa6f4"&gt;A good research question suggests an approach, methodology and hypothesis. &lt;strong&gt;Research questions guide all aspects of a study and are specific, detailed enough to require investigation, achievable in the time and financial constraints, and contribute to existing knowledge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-dd6ac84f-7fff-9e5b-6725-a479a2ffa6f4"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;A good research question will indicate what methodologies might not be appropriate in the study. Not all methods are suitable for all research questions, but several methods can be suitable for one research question. Similarly with hypotheses: a research question will suggest several potential hypotheses, and while several methodologies can be used to test a hypothesis, some methodologies just won’t provide the evidence needed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The research question needs to balance simplicity and complexity. It should be clear and precise enough for you to communicate to others; simple for others in your field to understand. This means you want to be specific not only about the subject of the study, but also what aspect of it you are testing, or the context or location of the study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The research question needs however to be complex enough to need to be studied. If it can be answered in a few days, then it’s perhaps only a sub-question of the bigger research question you are working towards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Appropriate research questions therefore take into account what time, resources, skills and experience are available to you. You can have a good research question, but not be in a position for it to research it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Good research is, most importantly, about expanding knowledge. It’s testing hypotheses, and answering questions to which you don't know the answer: whether that’s by having a correct or incorrect hypothesis. The unknown, and the discovery of new things, is what makes good research exciting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>11290</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>{"op":"&amp;","c":[],"showc":[]}</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>1692369180</timemodified>
  <course_format_options id="946">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>collapsed</name>
    <value>0</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="944">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>parent</name>
    <value>28</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="945">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>visibleold</name>
    <value>1</value>
  </course_format_options>
</section>