<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2313" moduleid="11711" modulename="label" contextid="87053">
  <label id="2313">
    <name>Bring together the four modules in this topic (def...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Bring together the four modules in this topic (&lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=196"&gt;defining&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=200"&gt;exploring&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=205"&gt;interactions&lt;/a&gt;, report, and &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=213"&gt;modelling&lt;/a&gt;) into a written report. The aim is to report your results from the Millet data, stating the variables and relationships that account for variability in the yield of Millet.&amp;nbsp; Ensure that you describe your methods and results for your explorations, analyses, and interpretations in this report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;This stage precedes the modelling phase, which will be addressed in the subsequent section. However, in the context of this opportunistic data, now is a good moment to start the writing process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;Writing up at this stage is useful for several reasons:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;Documenting the insights found when exploring and interpreting the data at this stage may result in a more articulate report of the patterns and observations in the data since they are fresh in your mind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Linking to 1., documenting at this stage could open up new paths of other avenues to explore. This can save time later if these avenues were considered when writing up &lt;em&gt;after &lt;/em&gt;modelling.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Writing up can also can give a broader perspective to guide decisions for modelling; for example, the assumptions for the model, the appropriate model type or distribution, or for the variables to select in the model.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Writing up now can give a solid foundation to refine as the process continues.&amp;nbsp;There will be some back and forth between the exploration, modelling, and writing up when you start modelling, so writing now does not necessarily mean that the exploration is "completed". However, if the exploration is performed thoroughly, then the modelling should confirm what you have found through exploring the data and interactions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Writing up now can be beneficial to share to a wider audience for feedback. This can help improve the research overall, and hence the findings, since you can communicate the research with others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693383932</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>