<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2332" moduleid="11801" modulename="label" contextid="87146">
  <label id="2332">
    <name>The Indian Dairy case study provides us with an in...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-13c90d19-7fff-faf7-d9db-1f5464b8a0dd"&gt;The &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=15" target="_blank"&gt;Indian Dairy case study&lt;/a&gt; provides us with an interesting example of research that explores the relationship between different levels of a system.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The researchers conducted a baseline survey at household level:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Collected quantitative and qualitative data addressed the socio-economic profile of the dairy producer, dairy herd composition and management with focus on breeding, health care and feeding, in- and output markets for dairy production and further agricultural activities following previous system topologies [16, 27].&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;They selected households according to the scale of their urbanisation, as demonstrated by the map below showing the geographic range of the selected settlements (using the Survey Stratification Index, SSI, to categorise urbanisation on a scale from 1 to 6).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/IujZgthfNGcuw9kbaYL-a1swm_xRCjbMsCgAAS3_jFZ18HPgjZe_B4M-zFbS8wQit34kyRDq_iGhqBojj1ZzIW-zMvop9UF39dcMkizNjoNRlnU4tZbNEV7e9vAUyvua-rp2UK14Y3iORVhodlyekMk" width="308" height="269"&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-03daf4fc-7fff-0adb-d277-a8db5d04571b"&gt;This two level approach enabled the researchers to analyse the household level data according to their urbanisation. The approach provides depth and breadth to understand the effects of urbanisation on dairy systems.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693436674</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>