<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2127" moduleid="11208" modulename="label" contextid="86129">
  <label id="2127">
    <name>Finalise your questionnaire in a digital format.Da...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;Finalise your questionnaire in a digital format.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-9a0337f3-7fff-e03b-5974-bcd375fab510"&gt;Data collection can be conducted through paper or digital tools. Both come with their own set of benefits and challenges. For example, paper questionnaires may be more accessible and pose fewer physical constraints on the person completing it, but can easily get damaged (by the weather, children, or pens that don’t work). Digital questionnaires can improve data cleaning, analysis and quality control, but may pose technical challenges to users.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-9a0337f3-7fff-e03b-5974-bcd375fab510"&gt;For this task, we will create a digital questionnaire. We will use Open Data Kit (ODK), which is an open-source digital data collection system extensively used worldwide, including in challenging low resource environments. It is regularly used by agricultural, health and humanitarian related disciplines, amongst others.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-9a0337f3-7fff-e03b-5974-bcd375fab510"&gt;ODK questionnaires can be authored in a spreadsheet, using XLSForms, a standardised structure which is easy to collaborate on in Microsoft Excel, GoogleSheets or any other spreadsheet. You can download and use &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/ODK%20XLSForm%20template.xlsx" target="_blank" title="this XLSForm template"&gt;this XLSForm template&lt;/a&gt; to help you get started. You will find a lot of useful information on the &lt;a href="https://docs.getodk.org/form-design-intro/" target="_blank" title="ODK website"&gt;ODK website&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://xlsform.org/en/" target="_blank" title="the XLSform website"&gt;the XLSform website&lt;/a&gt;, and answers to your questions in the &lt;a href="https://forum.getodk.org/" target="_blank" title="ODK community forum"&gt;ODK community forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-9a0337f3-7fff-e03b-5974-bcd375fab510"&gt;In all questionnaires, data input errors commonly occur. When building your forms, consider how you can minimise such errors. In digital forms, this might include selecting appropriate question types, adding constraints and relevance options. Do all questions need to be answered? If no, which ones should be optional, and why?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-9a0337f3-7fff-e03b-5974-bcd375fab510"&gt;To test and deploy your forms, we suggest you create a free account on &lt;a href="https://www.kobotoolbox.org/" target="_blank" title="KoboToolbox"&gt;KoboToolbox&lt;/a&gt;. Several platforms exist, but KoboToolbox will continue to be freely available to you after this course.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-9a0337f3-7fff-e03b-5974-bcd375fab510"&gt;Your KoboToolbox account will enable you to upload your XLSForm, test the logic and accuracy of your questionnaire, and view how data is stored and accessed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692778874</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>