<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2297" moduleid="11559" modulename="label" contextid="86853">
  <label id="2297">
    <name>We continue from the Illustrative Example in Explo...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;We continue from the Illustrative Example in &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=200"&gt;Exploration of Data&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=17#section-17" target="_blank"&gt;Niger climatic data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

We can visualise complexities in this data by using Facets and Layers to visualise multidimensionality. In Figure 1, the average rainfall values by year are given split by each month and station. There is an increase of average rainfall for all stations between April and October - peaking in August. However, this distribution of rainfall is different for the different stations: Agades experiences much less rainfall than the other stations on average. Therefore, there is an indication that the different stations experience different amounts of rainfall on average.&lt;br&gt;In addition, Zinder looks to be the rainiest station in August, but Niamey Aero is the rainiest station in July.&amp;nbsp;This suggests that the combination of month and station results in a different amount of rainfall on average. In other words, there is an indication of an interaction between Month, Station, and Rainfall.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/image.png" alt="" role="presentation" class="img-fluid"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1: Average yearly rainfall by Month and Station.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We can also look at the average yearly&amp;nbsp;rainfall by Year and Station (Figure 2).&lt;br&gt;If the lines overlapped, it would indicate that the average yearly rainfall is the same for all stations. But they do not overlap, implying that the&amp;nbsp;average yearly&amp;nbsp;rainfall differs depending on station (this is as expected given previous explorations so it is reassuring!).&lt;br&gt;If we have four Parallel lines, it would indicate that the average rainfall is changing the same amount across the years regardless of station. However, the lines are not parallel - there is an indication that rainfall is increasing at a different rate in Niamey Aero as the years increase compared to Birni N'Konni. In addition, the average rainfall seems to be decreasing in Agades as the years increase. It looks as if the context of the station is important when predicting rainfall. This is an interaction: If the lines are not parallel, then an interaction is present.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/image%20%281%29.png" alt="" role="presentation" class="img-fluid"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Average rainfall for each Year and Station.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;We saw previously when exploring the data that the relationship between tmin and rain is such that there is less rain under lower and higher temperatures.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;Is this the same for every station? We can investigate this (Figure 3).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/image%20%283%29.png" alt="" role="presentation" class="img-fluid" style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 3: Relationship between Rainfall and Minimum Temperature for each Station&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can see that the relationship between tmin and rain do alter slightly for the different stations: Agades experiences cooler temperatures than our other stations. Further, Zinder is slightly more symmetrical than Niamey Aero.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;We can add more layers, and look by the season (where dry season is Nov to Mar, and rainy season is otherwise).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/image%20%282%29.png" alt="" role="presentation" class="img-fluid"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 4: Relationship between Rainfall and Minimum Temperature for each Station and Season.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;This might be getting a little complex now looking at multiple levels at once. So, we can instead filter the data to a specific station. We are then just looking at the context of one region at a time. For example, you may focus on Agades first, and look at multidimensionality in that region. You can then look at another station individually. This can help reduce variability but still look into the context of a specific factor level, so still exploring multidimensionality.&lt;br&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693242855</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>