<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2624">
  <number>22</number>
  <name>Abstract Concept</name>
  <summary>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-5f299642-7fff-e91f-9478-5404cd65684b"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-64e2275b-7fff-e926-4562-a4ab4dc8afde"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;A literature review is about situating a study. It should be comprehensive, and provide evidence for the need or purpose of the study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research studies can be situated in two ways: contextually (e.g. geographically, socially, …), and within a theoretical framework.&lt;/strong&gt; Understanding the difference between these two, and how they interrelate, is the first step to a literature review.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;A theoretical framework lays out the big ideas that you want to engage with and connects your study with regional and global discussions. It lays out the assumptions behind the study and guides the methods used. The theoretical framework is mainly subject-specific, but can be developed through additional literature from a variety of subjects and disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;Subject-specific, contextual literature also needs to be engaged with. This grounded, local level to your literature review brings in the local context - relationship dynamics, techniques, infrastructure etc. - and can again be achieved through readings from different disciplines. Perhaps a theory works in one place but not in another; the contextual literature review helps answer this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>11281</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>{"op":"&amp;","c":[],"showc":[]}</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>1689685148</timemodified>
  <course_format_options id="919">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>collapsed</name>
    <value>0</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="917">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>parent</name>
    <value>20</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="918">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>visibleold</name>
    <value>1</value>
  </course_format_options>
</section>