<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2196" moduleid="11357" modulename="label" contextid="86607">
  <label id="2196">
    <name>The aim of analysis is to gain valuable insights i...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-dccbfb8a-7fff-2293-bd05-454ce051f2a1"&gt;The aim of analysis is to gain valuable insights into the relationships and trends within the data. This leads to a fundamental initial step which is to determine which variables to measure, or consider in the case of secondary research, and which variables to ignore.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-dccbfb8a-7fff-2293-bd05-454ce051f2a1"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Deciding this is not a step that should be taken lightly, and requires thought on the interpretation phase. Namely, the analyst should ask themselves: Are the variables measured able to answer the question?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;There are decisions to be made about what variables are considered/measured. These relate to the practical aspects of actually performing the experiment: How reliable is this measurement? How easy is it to measure, how expensive is it, how ethical is it, how much of it corresponds to what you actually care about? This can help minimise the cost and time spent and maximise the usefulness of findings&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any variables that are not measured are variables that are ignored.&lt;/strong&gt; Resources are finite: Ignoring variables can allow the resources and efforts in the study to be focussed on the more relevant aspects of the study objective(s). However, ignoring a variable should be thoughtful and well-justified - it should be a conscious choice to ignore it. This is to ensure that any excluded variables do not compromise the validity of the study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The basic design principles relating to controlling variability is in measurement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692903467</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>