<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2632">
  <number>29</number>
  <name>Illustrative example: research questions to understand suburban dairy systems</name>
  <summary>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-821ba776-7fff-77ad-cc0f-4052425bb0be"&gt;Do you think “what income does a cow provide to a farm?” is a good research question? No? What do you think is missing?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-821ba776-7fff-77ad-cc0f-4052425bb0be"&gt;Firstly, it’s too general to be really understood. What types of farm are we talking about and where? What breed of cow are we researching? A good research question should be specific and easy for others to understand clearly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-821ba776-7fff-77ad-cc0f-4052425bb0be"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-019d9dac-7fff-385e-542a-0f58b71fd4a5"&gt;Secondly, simple answers to this question exist already - and so the findings of this vague research question won’t bring any new knowledge or understanding. A good research question should be relevant for the subject and further knowledge.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-821ba776-7fff-77ad-cc0f-4052425bb0be"&gt;Thirdly, at its simplest, this question can be answered in 2 minutes by searching online - that’s achievable with just a smartphone and an internet connection, but it’s not suitable for a PhD study, for example. A good research question should be achievable and suitable for the study.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-821ba776-7fff-77ad-cc0f-4052425bb0be"&gt;Let’s look at a real example of a research question from a&lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=15" target="_blank"&gt; case study of Dairy Production in India&lt;/a&gt;, take this paragraph from &lt;a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0255791" target="_blank" title="Reichenbach et al."&gt;Reichenbach et al.&lt;/a&gt; 2021:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-821ba776-7fff-77ad-cc0f-4052425bb0be"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In the 1970s’, the Indian government launched a decades-long development program called Operation Flood that focused on dairy production as a vital rural-urban linkage [21]. Operation Flood successfully scaled up rural milk production, marketing and processing through dairy cooperatives and improved infrastructures, to supply urban areas [21]. Thus, taking dairy production in Bengaluru, India, as an example for production systems in an urbanizing environment and a discussion point on social-ecological linkages in the same context, the present study considers urban, peri-urban and rural areas in and around an emerging megacity to tackle the following research questions: do distinct dairy production systems (DPS) coexist along a rural-urban interface and how are they impacted by urbanization? To answer these questions, we surveyed 337 dairy producers in and around the emerging megacity of Bengaluru in southern India.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-821ba776-7fff-77ad-cc0f-4052425bb0be"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Reichenbach M, Pinto A, König S, Bhatta R, Schlecht E. 2021. Dairy production in an urbanizing environment—Typology and linkages in the megacity of Bengaluru, India. PLoS ONE 16(8): e0255791&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-821ba776-7fff-77ad-cc0f-4052425bb0be"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Reichenbach et al. are interested in agricultural systems that cross or connect rural and urban environments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Their research questions are clear and easy to understand, and made specific by the addition of the geographic context (Bengaluru, India).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Are there research questions going to further knowledge and understanding? Yes! The questions are broad enough that they will produce findings to contribute to our understanding of farming and urbanization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Do the research questions seem realistic and achievable? Yes! Their methodology and narrow focus means they could manage to survey 337 dairy producers in a multi-year research project. They also highlight that there is existing literature on the topic, which would inform the study and give it more depth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>11289</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>{"op":"&amp;","c":[],"showc":[]}</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>1692604235</timemodified>
  <course_format_options id="943">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>collapsed</name>
    <value>0</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="941">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>parent</name>
    <value>28</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="942">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>visibleold</name>
    <value>1</value>
  </course_format_options>
</section>