<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2256" moduleid="11472" modulename="label" contextid="86728">
  <label id="2256">
    <name>How good is a solution if people don’t actually wa...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;How good is a solution if people don’t actually want to use or adopt it?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;FUMA Gaskiya, a farmer federation in Niger which is deeply engaged in agroecological research, came up against several such challenges when &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Sanitized%20human%20urine%20%28Oga%29%20as%20a%20fertilizer%20auto-innovation%20from%20women%20farmers%20in%20Niger.pdf"&gt;studying the potentials of using human urine as a fertiliser.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The use of sanitized human urine locally known as “Oga” is one of the AEI options. Oga means “the boss” in Igbo language, an ethnic group in south-east Nigeria. Oga is commonly used in Nigeria in public and government offices to show respect to someone in a position of authority. Because urine application is seen as a taboo among some ethnic groups like Peulh, the name Oga was proposed by a farmer as replacement. Therefore, the term Oga is not an abbreviation, and will be used in the following. At first most farmers were reluctant about Oga application due to religious and sanitary reasons. To convince farmers to test and apply Oga, the project team encouraged farmers to combine Oga with organic wastes and dung in the first and second year of the project. These local farmers, having seen positive results, were convinced to apply solely Oga in subsequent years. Formal discussions were held with religious leaders and medical experts on the stand of Koran and sanitary aspects, respectively. Cultural and social aspects of Oga were discussed. In general, Oga has neither religious, cultural, social, nor sanitary barriers. A video clip was projected in selected villages, shared through WhatsApp and YouTube platforms to create awareness about the positive effects of Oga and its general acceptance. This story is documented online in a video (www.youtube.com/watch?v= 0WpGKK7roZ4&amp;amp;vl=fr) (Fig. 1).”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span&gt;H. O. Moussa, C. I. Nwankwo, A. M. Aminou, D. A. Stern, B. I. G. Haussmann and L. Herrmann. 2021. Sanitized human urine (Oga) as a fertilizer auto-innovation from women farmers in Niger. &lt;em&gt;Agronomy for Sustainable Development&lt;/em&gt;. 41(4): 56.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The researchers identified that encouraging people to discuss human urine, let alone using it, would be difficult. One of the farmers they worked with was aware of this and made a suggestion for an alternative, code word, to replace the word urine: Oga. This highlights the importance of the words we use!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Another challenge in researching human urine as a fertiliser was to ensure compliance with religious, medical and cultural norms. We see the researchers held formal discussions with relevant leaders to validate the safety of Oga use on the farm. Working with leaders from the start of the project can help ensure that innovations are well received.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The importance of including local values and motivations in research is also highlighted in the FAO’s agroecological principle: Food and cultural traditions.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693174070</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>