<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2246" moduleid="11462" modulename="label" contextid="86718">
  <label id="2246">
    <name>Examining the error term gives insights into the m...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-349b8911-7fff-4139-81c7-7bd3c8346f86"&gt;Examining the error term gives insights into the model. Looking at the plots can examine if there is more variability that could be accounted for.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-349b8911-7fff-4139-81c7-7bd3c8346f86"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;First we will look at the general distribution of the outcome variable. Then the distribution of the error term.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Distribution of the Outcome Variable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;The outcome variable tells a lot about the appropriate model to fit. If the data is continuous and normally distributed, a linear regression model is a suitable choice. This is a simple model which fits a linear relationship between the explanatory variables and the outcome variable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;If the data follows a non-normal distribution, however, a generalised linear model (GLM) is appropriate. GLMs can handle an array of data distributions allowing it to be applicable to many different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;For example, in Figure 1, generated data of a normally-distributed variable and a skewed variable are shown through boxplots and histograms. The “Normal” distribution is roughly symmetric, whereas the skewed distribution is … not so symmetric.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/dQ-swQf513DqlituVejVy1xnhAobH91R826T-uZ3Af2XFz4WfL3gCGeyEovVxYUdq5nrkdKqjMUxuq8Ti4PVk3lGUMqFCTuDJHWxDgGS4-VSJUZxDBX59tXFemYjkXkf2oPhQyIe-e95_hPm0HNEcss" width="624" height="492"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;Figure 1: Four plots demonstrating a Normal and Skewed distribution in an outcome variable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Distribution of the Error Term&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;We can also examine the distribution of the error term after fitting a model. This is linked to the distribution of the outcome variable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;The error term, often referred to as the “residuals”, is the difference between the observed values and the predicted values when the model is fitted to the observed data. There is more information on What are residuals here&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;If we fit a linear model, and the distribution of the error term is normal, then we would expect &lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;a plot of the residuals against the fitted values would show no pattern at all. Just random scattering, like in the top figure in Figure 2. Secondly, a QQ-plot would display the points on a 45-degree straight diagonal line, along y = x, like in the bottom figure in Figure 2.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/zwrANrhNHl6q6PVPn_m12zt-VvxQ3TLIUV4gq9DoUOvyKGL90ykrmUzWcpUE4uj6UBrhpKquq3ubeD-RffwU5hn46z7TSFEVDT58AO2YLxakr9itB98epS5D1KdNxZMNI7jC2-pAMCuAcxpOKZLa0RE" width="624" height="399"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4WwJBMEI2E6t2Ioq2g5xqRAAHm5a0U_X2hGGQ7hYIJfp6FxeSTJHiMouN9VisiAwadTPmVLHJU5mxs33tpAfyC9Jg3nv5xdwUBv6x87k6uHfw_ObPcrehEGBA8hRxehKSYVmlKfBkLtmQm7P8HeCb1U" width="624" height="399"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 2: Plot of the Residual terms after fitting a model. These plots illustrate that a Linear Model has been correctly fitted to a Normally distributed outcome variable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693172218</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>