<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2137" moduleid="11221" modulename="label" contextid="86151">
  <label id="2137">
    <name>As academic researchers, we want to connect and sh...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-0c072486-7fff-456b-5bce-2dd5a189528a"&gt;As academic researchers, we want to connect and share our findings with several audiences. One of our main audiences is the academic community, who will benefit from the new learnings identified from your research. If you want to have impact beyond academia however, you will be thinking about communicating your findings with local communities or with change makers such as policymakers. How you communicate your findings will depend on who you want to communicate with.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-0c072486-7fff-456b-5bce-2dd5a189528a"&gt;Let’s consider the &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=14" target="_blank"&gt;Participatory Integrated Climate Services for Agriculture (PICSA) article,&lt;/a&gt; this is an academic article published in the Climate Services journal. The audience will mainly be researchers in climate services, that is the use and application of climate and weather knowledge, and so the journal is intended to be read not only by researchers but also practitioners or stakeholders of climate services. Looking at the introductory section, do you think the stated aims of the article are suitable for the Climate Services journal audience?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-0c072486-7fff-456b-5bce-2dd5a189528a"&gt;“&lt;em&gt;This paper introduces the PICSA approach and then using the example of Northern Ghana where PICSA was implemented for the first time to scale (more than five thousand farmers in 2015 season) aims to investigate whether and how PICSA affected both i) farmers’ decisions and actions and ii) their livelihoods.&lt;/em&gt;” Page 3.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-0c072486-7fff-456b-5bce-2dd5a189528a"&gt;Graham Clarkson, Peter Dorward, Henny Osbahr, Francis Torgbor, Isaac Kankam-Boadu, 2019.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;An investigation of the effects of PICSA on smallholder farmers’ decision-making and livelihoods when implemented at large scale – The case of Northern Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Climate Services&lt;/em&gt;, 14: 1-14.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-0c072486-7fff-456b-5bce-2dd5a189528a"&gt;The PICSA article does seem to have been written for the subsection of the academic audience who will read the Climate Services journal: the readers will be interested in how to train and share climate and weather knowledge with communities, but will likely not be familiar with the PICSA approach.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-0c072486-7fff-456b-5bce-2dd5a189528a"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;Academic research articles tend to follow a similar structure, see the image of the navigation panel. This navigation panel is what we are now used to in Microsoft Word, Google Documents and equivalent packages, when long documents are usefully subdivided into sections through the use of headings and subheadings.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/hOm4eqH1K3hAXzLR_osuzf7_kfMl_o6hI3aLv8lACPDs8ukAsBYpigIwkD2PxlGjtqnuecA23Pf2kAy-fA6dc0sNswgQsr0JbcDx9CGhvwBWeSEWWYnKkuAqwK7Gbh2pbXlR_KHDXPwWwrZsGY4vT9I" width="198" height="405"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The PICSA article is structured, as is common for academic papers, into four sections: introduction, methods, results and discussion. They distinguish between their PICSA training approach and the research methods used in the article, and their results section is subdivided into six subheadings which build in complexity: from an overview of the characteristics of the research participants and their perspectives of the PICSA training, to what changes have been made and the impact of these decisions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;If this was not an academic article but a report for funders, or an evidence brief to advocate for policy change, the structure and tone would be quite different!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692581093</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>