<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2124" moduleid="11204" modulename="label" contextid="86117">
  <label id="2124">
    <name>The write-up process can start even before data co...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The write-up process can start even before data collection begins.&lt;/strong&gt; By reporting and documenting progress as you go, rather than relying solely on memory, you can maintain a comprehensive and accurate account of the study from start to finish. This can save you time and is part of a reflective process that helps you communicate your study to others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-722dbbee-7fff-9665-2dc9-11e6e559cc2b"&gt;Consider firstly how you will document your study and all decision-making steps. What are you most comfortable doing, what is efficient, and how will this documentation translate into your report?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-722dbbee-7fff-9665-2dc9-11e6e559cc2b"&gt;Secondly, consider how do you want to communicate your findings to others? Consider who you want to communicate your findings with and use &lt;a href="$@RESOURCEVIEWBYID*11268@$" target="_blank" title="this template"&gt;this template&lt;/a&gt; to help structure your report.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-722dbbee-7fff-9665-2dc9-11e6e559cc2b"&gt;Now that you have decided how to document your activities, and how you will report on your study, consider your data and your data collection methods. We have decided to use Open Data Kit (ODK) digital questionnaires as a data collection method as learning how to use ODK is a key objective for this course, but what sort of data will your questionnaire create? How will you analyse the data collected? What skills and experiences do you have that you could use?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-722dbbee-7fff-9665-2dc9-11e6e559cc2b"&gt;How much of your report can you write before collecting data? The report should be completed as you go along, not at the end of the study.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692634242</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>