<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2628">
  <number>26</number>
  <name>Abstract Concept</name>
  <summary>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-f4486e4f-7fff-2802-3465-a839f9868332"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading for academic purposes is a balance between reading fast and reading slow.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-0f9c3875-7fff-a98d-7e64-70d9e6d8e254"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;Fast reading is for awareness. There are so many available texts related to your study, you need to be able to efficiently get an awareness of what is out there. Before investing time in a text, ask yourself how it might contribute to your theoretical or contextual knowledge. You don’t need to read every word when reading academically, you can focus on just what is relevant - skim reading is a great skill to learn. Watch out though, the author may have different perspectives elsewhere in the paper!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;Slow reading is about understanding. Often, you will find yourself needing time to reflect on what you’re reading about. You might need to do added research to make sure you understand what is being discussed. You will rarely slow read a whole paper, and instead will slow read a specific component or section. It sounds obvious when written down, but if you’re reading for theoretical knowledge, focus on the theory described in a study. If the paper is contextually interesting to your study, take the time to notice these details. Introductions and conclusions often contain the most important ideas, so prioritise reading these.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr" style=""&gt;When reading, you should be critically engaging with what the authors are describing. Critical thinking means asking what can be improved and how? So reading is not just about understanding something, it’s also about how to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>11284</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>{"op":"&amp;","c":[],"showc":[]}</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>1689685277</timemodified>
  <course_format_options id="931">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>collapsed</name>
    <value>0</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="929">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>parent</name>
    <value>24</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="930">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>visibleold</name>
    <value>1</value>
  </course_format_options>
</section>