<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="1780" moduleid="10045" modulename="label" contextid="84105">
  <label id="1780">
    <name>We designed an experiment&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;analysed t...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=123"&gt;designed an experiment&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=128"&gt;analysed the data&lt;/a&gt; to look at the effect of the treatments on the yield of tomatoes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We want to put our analysis into context. This section is on the &lt;strong&gt;interpretation&lt;/strong&gt; of this data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When interpreting, you want to take into account the objectives:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Our first objective is to recommend the strategy of growing
tomatoes that maximises the yield.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. The
second objective is for the researchers to recommend the strategy of growing tomatoes
taking some account of cost of the different treatments.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-ce658d01-7fff-451f-6051-32c74795d96c"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;Suppose you are going to grow one greenhouse of tomatoes and that the extra costs of supplementary heating and lighting are £500 and £400 for the whole greenhouse respectively with no difference in the cost of varieties.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;Say that a plot mean increase in yield of one unit the increase in income for your whole greenhouse is £200. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-ce658d01-7fff-451f-6051-32c74795d96c" style=""&gt;The aim here is to interpret your results, accounting for the cost of the different treatments.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;Have a think about which treatment combination is best economically.&amp;nbsp; Is this the same combination which gave the highest yield?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400; font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;We want to recommend the strategy of growing tomatoes, taking some account of cost of the different treatments.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1692888005</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>