<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2287" moduleid="11527" modulename="label" contextid="86813">
  <label id="2287">
    <name>Research that involves or relates to people should...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Research that involves or relates to people should consider their preferences or experiences. Quantitative research methods can explore the breadth or scale of a situation, whilst qualitative research methods support the exploration of these ideas in depth, and enable the identification of unexpected priorities, needs and wants. Often we need to both methods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=14" target="_blank"&gt;Participatory Integrated Climate Services for Agriculture (PICSA) team&lt;/a&gt;wanted to evaluate their program, which means that they wanted to capture not only people’s experiences, but also these unexpected aspects that had resulted in the climate training. They combined a range of quantitative and qualitative research methods to evaluate the impact of their training and perceptions of these changes. Can you identify the different research methods used in PICSA’s evaluation, and how they supported different aspects of the research question?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“As part of PICSA implementation there are monitoring sheets for agricultural field officers to fill out after every one of their meetings with groups of farmers. Farmers were interviewed for short surveys … when farmers make decisions about the coming season … and … after the season… In addition to these short surveys, monitoring is conducted during the season through field visits by trained PICSA experts ... In the north of Ghana implementation in 2015 there were two separate visits by a research assistant who used observation, focus group discussions and in-depth individual interviews with farmers to investigate the impact that PICSA was having on households’ decision making. After the season a review meeting was held with all intermediaries that had been involved in the initial training and roll-out of the PICSA approach to be able to hear their thoughts and experiences and to provide support for their interactions with farmers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the north of Ghana, initial findings from these elements of PICSA monitoring helped to design a mixed methods approach that combined a quantitative survey of 416 randomly selected households that had received PICSA training and in depth qualitative case studies with 18 PICSA trained farmers. The quantitative survey covered six districts across the northern region of Ghana (see Fig. 3) and each contained communities that had established farmer groups working with ADRA. The quantitative survey was carried out by independent enumerators using tablets and Open Data Kit software2. This was followed by qualitative case study fieldwork that involved 18 of those households which were purposively sampled following initial analysis of the quantitative survey data. These households were chosen based upon categorisation drawn from the quantitative survey to make sure there was an accurate representation of genders, those who had made changes in crops, livestock and livelihoods and those that had made no changes based on the PICSA approach. The quantitative survey and qualitative case study methodology were carefully developed and then piloted. The quantitative survey included a range of closed questions, open-ended questions and Likert style statements. The qualitative case studies initially involved mainly open-ended questions to capture farmer reflections and experiences before providing more detail by using PBs [personal bests] and effects diagrams to understand the real impact and effect of changes farmers had made.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;…The qualitative case studies, through in-depth discussion, interviewing and observation, also allowed for triangulation to ensure correct attribution of changes and reported effects due to the PICSA training. The research focused mainly on whether and how PICSA influenced farmers’ behaviours, and at farmers’ perceptions of the effects of their changed behaviours. It also explored farmers’ perceptions of their ability and confidence to make decisions, and deal with climate related challenges etc.” Pages 5-6.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Graham Clarkson, Peter Dorward, Henny Osbahr, Francis Torgbor, Isaac Kankam-Boadu, 2019. An investigation of the effects of PICSA on smallholder farmers’ decision-making and livelihoods when implemented at large scale – The case of Northern Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Climate Services&lt;/em&gt;, 14: 1-14.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;PICSA as an approach uses several methods to monitor its impact. There are monitoring sheets, short surveys and monitoring visits that use observation, focus group discussions and interviews.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;To evaluate their approach, the PICSA researchers additionally created a quantitative survey of 416 households and 18 qualitative case studies of farms. The research evaluation team therefore conducted a survey study of PICSA-trained households, and combined this with an opportunistic study approach whereby they made use of their existing, routinely collected monitoring data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;A benefit of these multiple methods is that the results can be checked for consistency. Using several methods, and comparing the results, is a research equivalent of repeating experiments on a farm: the repetition, or different methods, can elicit different results or responses and help identify the reasons behind variation. Working with people, you often find that there might be variation because people don’t know what they do or think, or they don’t want to say what they do or think! On the other hand consistent results across approaches increases the confidence in study findings.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693225251</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>