<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2316" moduleid="11714" modulename="label" contextid="87056">
  <label id="2316">
    <name>FUMA Gaskiya, a farmer federation in Niger, collab...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-b280341d-7fff-fac1-0e35-cc87bf3b37d0"&gt;FUMA Gaskiya, a farmer federation in Niger, collaborates with researchers to improve the soil health for the most vulnerable in the community, as defined by the community themselves. The &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Sanitized%20human%20urine%20%28Oga%29%20as%20a%20fertilizer%20auto-innovation%20from%20women%20farmers%20in%20Niger.pdf"&gt;article excerpt&lt;/a&gt; below draws out key aspects of this collaboration, and some considerations for researchers working with farmers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-b280341d-7fff-fac1-0e35-cc87bf3b37d0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This research profited from a long-term collaboration of stakeholders in agronomic research, i.e., international and national research as well as two farmer federations. The long-term collaboration (&amp;gt; 10 years) provided a sound and reliable framework and trust for conducting the relatively large number of on-farm trials on an agronomic innovation. Farmers must have the confidence that the innovation is not setting them at risk. Research stakeholders need trust that the data are collected in the right manner. So, we have a case of mutual dependency that needs to be dealt with in an open manner. Mutual respect and continuous learning on both sites are a prerequisite for success. Therefore, it should be allowed to change the trial protocol between seasons if recent results or pertinent arguments propose it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-b280341d-7fff-fac1-0e35-cc87bf3b37d0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Large-N trials are usually characterized by a nonequilibrated data set and in consequence a lower statistic force. In particular if—on the run—new villages or farmers are introduced in the trial design—point data loss is programmed and needs to be dealt with. In long-term trials—as the present case—it makes sense to give more freedom to farmers with respect to management of the trial sites.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-b280341d-7fff-fac1-0e35-cc87bf3b37d0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;While it is convenient for the researcher to work with ceteris paribus conditions at the beginning in order to reduce heterogeneity in the trials, more variance in later stages improves the potential for site adapted recommendations. E.g., for farmers who practice urea fertilization at booting stage anyway, it does not make sense to apply Oga for a second time. Sometimes farmers make their own observations and then change the “protocol”. E.g., it was observed that Oga application reduces certain pest attacks (according to farmers presumably due to the odor). In consequence, timing of the application might be changed, or the application is done for other reasons than nutrient application. Researchers should be aware of this possibility and should not try to block these opportunities, because otherwise they obtain falsely reported data that can hardly be interpreted. Also, these farmer observations can result in other local innovations that benefit smallholder farmers.”&lt;/em&gt; Page 11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-b280341d-7fff-fac1-0e35-cc87bf3b37d0"&gt;Moussa, H.O., Nwankwo, C.I., Aminou, A.M. et al. Sanitized human urine (Oga) as a fertilizer auto-innovation from women farmers in Niger. &lt;em&gt;Agron. Sustain. Dev&lt;/em&gt;. 41, 56 (2021).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-b280341d-7fff-fac1-0e35-cc87bf3b37d0"&gt;Collaborations need to be based on a shared interest and relationships of trust and respect. An openness to learning, as mentioned here, and a flexibility to change when needed, also makes way for issues to be dealt with easily.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693347672</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>