<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2272" moduleid="11506" modulename="label" contextid="86781">
  <label id="2272">
    <name>The Participatory Integrated Climate Services for ...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=14" target="_blank"&gt;Participatory Integrated Climate Services for Agriculture (PICSA) team&lt;/a&gt; wanted to evaluate their approach to supporting smallholder farmer use of climate information in the management of their farms. This means that the researchers were interested in understanding the farmer’s perspectives of the training they received, and its impact on them and their farms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The qualitative case studies initially involved mainly open-ended questions to capture farmer reflections and experiences before providing more detail by using PBs [Participatory Budgets] and effects diagrams to understand the real impact and effect of changes farmers had made…&amp;nbsp; The qualitative case studies, through in-depth discussion, interviewing and observation, also allowed for triangulation to ensure correct attribution of changes and reported effects due to the PICSA training. The research focused mainly on whether and how PICSA influenced farmers’ behaviours, and at farmers’ perceptions of the effects of their changed behaviours. It also explored farmers’ perceptions of their ability and confidence to make decisions, and deal with climate related challenges etc. …&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The case studies … included exploring in detail farmers’ perceptions of both tangible material changes that they attributed to the changed behaviours (e.g. yields and income) and other important benefits they had observed e.g. effects on food security, reduced need to seek employment elsewhere to supplement income and food, greater ability to pay for children’s education.” Pages 5-6.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Graham Clarkson, Peter Dorward, Henny Osbahr, Francis Torgbor, Isaac Kankam-Boadu, 2019.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style="font-size: 0.9375rem;"&gt;An investigation of the effects of PICSA on smallholder farmers’ decision-making and livelihoods when implemented at large scale – The case of Northern Ghana. &lt;em&gt;Climate Services&lt;/em&gt;, 14: 1-14.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The researchers used qualitative research methods and specify that they used open-ended questions. Open-ended questions allow for an exploration of an idea or topic and crucially, give people the opportunity to respond in ways which the researchers may not have been able to predict. This openness to the unexpected is a valuable aspect of qualitative research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The PICSA evaluation highlights several qualitative research methods: discussions, interviews and observation of the farmer’s activities. Together, these methods brought together a rich collection of information about individual farm practices and gave the researchers a deeper understanding of the farm’s activities and how these might have changed following the PICSA training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;It’s interesting to think of the qualitative research methods in terms of their structure. Some methods, like surveys or interviews, can be very structured with a pre-determined list of questions which the researcher will work their way through. We often talk about structured, or semi-structured interviews for example, to distinguish between interviews which do and don’t allow freedom to respond to comments and issues raised by the interviewee. Other methods, like observation or discussions, tend to be at the other end of the structure scale and can be thought of as semi-structured or unstructured. Unstructured observations or discussions are when the researcher ‘go with the flow’ and follow the lead of the people they are working with. In the text excerpt from the PICSA case study, we’re not told how structured their methods were, but it’s likely that they opted for semi-structured methods, given the focus of their research question and the fact that they mainly used open-ended questions.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693216804</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>