<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2299" moduleid="11562" modulename="label" contextid="86857">
  <label id="2299">
    <name>Gender is an important lens through which to under...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Gender is an important lens through which to understand farming systems. To fully understand a farm system, we need to take into consideration the implications and impacts of gender on different aspects of a farm system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;An interesting example comes from &lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Sanitized%20human%20urine%20%28Oga%29%20as%20a%20fertilizer%20auto-innovation%20from%20women%20farmers%20in%20Niger.pdf"&gt;FUMA Gaskiya’s research in Niger&lt;/a&gt; to improve the soil health of women’s fields:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In several countries including central Niger at the beginning of the cropping season, spouses mandatorily first have to help their husbands (Safilios-Rothschild 1985) to install the major staple crops. As a result, women can take care of their farmlands only later in the season. However, late planting reduces the potential crop yield (Reddy and Visser 1993), simply due to a shortened growth period in seasonal climates as well as leached nutrients with high intensity rains at the beginning of the season. This is particularly true in semi-arid regions like the Sahel, where the vegetation period is per se extremely short (i.e., ≤ 90 days). For these reasons, it makes sense to focus more on management options that support women…&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;African women are less likely to adopt innovations due to lack of access to information and the required resources, and partially due to lower decision-making power (Doss 2001). An important question is: what characteristics should innovation targeting women farmers possess in order to increase the chances of adoption? They should be (i) easy to apply, (ii) effective, (iii) based on local resources, (iv) accessible, and (v) bear low transport costs and economic risks. In addition, innovations should not be in contradiction to the cultural and religious habits and beliefs of the target people. Considering all these pre-requisites, the seedball technology seems to fit quite well apart from workload associated with its mass production. However, this technology particularly targets phosphorus nutrient enhancement (Nwankwo et al. 2018). In most Sahelian sandy soils (Arenosols according to the WRB (2015)), multiple nutrient deficiencies occur (Voortman 2010) that can best be counteracted by organic fertilizer that are per se containing a multitude of plant nutrients. Therefore, a cheap, simple, and effective holistic approach to mitigate the low chemical fertility status of women’s fields could be the application of sanitized human urine in combination with organic manure (OM). The urine would mainly supply nitrogen and potassium, while the OM would add other nutrients including some phosphorus.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;This section highlights several systems considered by the researchers. Amongst others, they mention the farming and cropping season system; the household (or spousal) sharing of work system; wider social systems (religious, cultural etc.); soil nutrient systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Systems thinking requires understanding the interactions between the different components and the possible impact that changes to one component might have on other aspects of the system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;So for example, the seedball technology mentioned above is not considered appropriate due to a) the high production workload it requires, which is unsuitable in the social context and b) the seedball’s phosphorus-rich characteristics, which do not suit the soil context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Human urine as a fertiliser is considered a potential option however, as it coincides with the needs of the social and soil systems to be cheap, accessible and simple, whilst also providing essential nutrients to the soil in this context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;In the &lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=222" target="_blank"&gt;Values and Motivations section&lt;/a&gt;, we see also that the potential use of Oga needs to be validated as ‘safe’ by potential users for it to be a viable option.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The FAO principle of &lt;em&gt;circular and solidarity economy&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;is an example of systems thinking, as connecting producers and consumers can develop local markets and strengthen local economic development to form an interdependent system based on solidarity.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693248419</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>