<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2644">
  <number>41</number>
  <name>Illustrative example: impact in pearl millet biofortification research</name>
  <summary>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e8618504-7fff-1b06-22f4-84df639e3f54"&gt;What kind of impact will your study have? Will it develop theoretical, or conceptual knowledge about our world and how we understand it? Or will it directly impact local communities?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e8618504-7fff-1b06-22f4-84df639e3f54"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Your research question determines what impact your study will have, and the impact domain directs your research methods.&lt;/span&gt; Knowing what impact you hope to achieve also helps you monitor and evaluate the success of your project.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e8618504-7fff-1b06-22f4-84df639e3f54"&gt;Let’s consider this article by Pucher et al. 2014 entitled “&lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=12" target="_blank"&gt;Micronutrient Density and Stability in West African Pearl Millet — Potential for Biofortification&lt;/a&gt;”. What sort of impact will it have?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e8618504-7fff-1b06-22f4-84df639e3f54"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Biofortification is the process of increasing the nutrient densities by breeding or genetic engineering. Biofortification of staple crops can be a sustainable and cost-effective approach to combating malnutrition (Bouis, 1999; Meenakshi et al., 2010)... The development of pearl millet varieties with improved grain mineral nutrient densities can be one step to improve the nutrient intake of rural families, especially in the Sahel region of sub-Saharan Africa where pearl millet can contribute 80 to 85% of daily calorie intake. Pearl millet biofortification, targeting increased grain Fe densities, has already been successful in India, where a biofortified, open-pollinated variety (OPV) was released in 2012 (Saltzman et al., 2013)... The success of the pearl millet biofortification program in India suggests that a comparable breeding program could be successful in WCA...&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e8618504-7fff-1b06-22f4-84df639e3f54"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pearl-millet-based dishes consumed in West Africa are traditionally prepared from decorticated grains, whereas nearly all pearl-millet-based dishes consumed in India are traditionally prepared from whole-grain flour. The decortification process is known to reduce mineral densities, and it is therefore relevant to analyze the relationship between whole and decorticated grain mineral densities.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e8618504-7fff-1b06-22f4-84df639e3f54"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=""&gt;Pucher, A., H. Høgh-Jensen, J. Gondah, C. T. Hash, and B. I. G. Haussmann. 2014. Micronutrient Density and Stability in West African Pearl Millet — Potential for Biofortification.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt; Crop Science &lt;/em&gt;54:1709–1720&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e8618504-7fff-1b06-22f4-84df639e3f54"&gt;Pucher et al.’s research aims to combat malnutrition in West Africa and so seek impact at scale. Similar research into pearl millet biofortification has been conducted in India to combat malnutrition, so the concept of the research in not original, but the application of the concept to a particular geographic area is. Not all research should be based on original concepts, and indeed it is very useful to apply existing knowledge to new or different local contexts. Impactful studies come in many forms!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e8618504-7fff-1b06-22f4-84df639e3f54"&gt;The researchers, notably B.I.G. Haussmann, are known for using participatory breeding research methods, where farmers are involved in testing and breeding new seed varieties, and this method highlights the importance of local impact to their studies. Involving local communities supports the development of locally appropriate, practical solutions that will be adopted by the populations concerned.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span id="docs-internal-guid-e8618504-7fff-1b06-22f4-84df639e3f54"&gt;It’s important to avoid doing research that is neither original nor impactful. The impact of Pucher et al.’s study would be greatly reduced if they had not, for example, considered the West African context of eating decorticated grains.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>11297</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>{"op":"&amp;","c":[],"showc":[]}</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>1692557807</timemodified>
  <course_format_options id="979">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>collapsed</name>
    <value>0</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="977">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>parent</name>
    <value>40</value>
  </course_format_options>
  <course_format_options id="978">
    <format>flexsections</format>
    <name>visibleold</name>
    <value>1</value>
  </course_format_options>
</section>