<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="2242" moduleid="11458" modulename="label" contextid="86714">
  <label id="2242">
    <name>Have you noticed how soil looks different dependin...</name>
    <intro>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Have you noticed how soil looks different depending on where you are and what the weather is like? Not only can soil be moist or dry, but amongst numerous other characteristics it can for example be acid or alkaline, nutrient rich or poor, or sandy or luminous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;To effectively and sustainably support agroecological workers, as researchers we need to develop a range of solutions that can enhance their productivity and efficiency. Conventional agricultural research has provided many benefits, but overall the approach seeks to optimise crop yield through simplified and standardized approaches, which have been proven to be damaging and not suitable for our varied and changing world. Modern agroecology embraces the detail of local variance, needs and contexts and recognises that this variance exists even at the level of a farm, where field environments may differ, or farmer needs may change year to year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The article &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="$@COURSEVIEWBYID*238@$&amp;amp;section=13" target="_blank"&gt;Post Stratification Clarifies Treatment Effects on Pearl Millet Growth in the Sahel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is an interesting example to consider, as the article is the result of researchers not knowing how to take variability, in this case soil variability, into account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Most current research focuses on blanket application of crop residues and mineral P fertilizer to sustain production on acid sandy soils of the Sahel (Bationo and Mokwunye, 1991; Bationo et al., 1993). However, given the multiple uses of crop residues by small-scale farmers of the Sahel and their scarce on-farm availability (Nicou and Charreau, 1985; Lamers and Fei1, 1993; Bationo et al. , 1995) crop residue application needs to be optimized. The data presented here suggest that concentrating available CR on spots of low productivity may be a short-term solution for restoring soil fertility on acid sandy soils of the Sahel. This is already practiced by some farmers in the region. However, our data also indicate that the transfer of crop residues from areas of high to low productivity may lead to a rapid decline of soil fertility in the former. A similarly rapid decline in millet yield after cessation of crop residue application has been found by Rebafka et al. (1994) and indicates how fragile the current agricultural systems are. All available data show that the continuous cultivation of acid sandy soils in the Sahel and a sustainable food production for the rapidly increasing agropastoral population in sub-Saharan Africa requires inputs of mineral fertilizers such as P. Only improved soil fertility will lead to higher grain and straw yields, which also would allow the application of crop residues on areas of both currently high and low productivity in farmers’ fields to prevent soil degradation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;CONCLUSIONS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The results presented here show that the short-term response of millet growth to CR application strongly depend on inherent soil productivity. They demonstrate the advantages of dividing a field into strata representing different soil productivity classes, and not simply into regular blocks, to better understand treatment effects. Until the mechanisms governing soil microvariability on the acid sandy soils of the Sahel are fully understood and the parameters involved can be easily determined, scoring of young millet plants may be a cheap and efficient approach to estimating differences in the expression of soil fertility in millet growth. This approach should be further tested and adapted to other soils and crops in the region to define the limits of its value in clarifying treatment effects and reducing experimental error.” pp760.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="editor-indent" style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Buerkert, Andreas, Roger D. Stern, and Horst Marschner. 1995. Post Stratification Clarifies Treatment Effects on Pearl Millet Growth in the Sahel. &lt;em&gt;Agronomy Journal&lt;/em&gt; 87(4): 752-761.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The researchers identified a challenge faced by farmers - and researchers - in the Sahel region that comes from the high variability of soil health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;As this example shows, variability of environments and contexts is a source of new avenues of research and new opportunities for impactful research. It can lead to new methods, techniques, crop varieties, and more appropriate options for farmers. For example, researchers can conduct multienvironment trials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Just as biodiversity provides vast benefits, the variability and diversity of contexts, an FAO agroecological principle, should also be embraced as an opportunity by researchers!&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <timemodified>1693242958</timemodified>
  </label>
</activity>